Establishing Models in Industrial Innovation
After its competitor invented the front loading washing machine , the CEO of the American IM company believed that each of its employees had the ability for innovation , and formulated strategic countermeasures for innovation in the industry .
1. Establish an innovation fund with a maximum amount of 1,000 <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> dollars .
2. Choose 100 innovative concepts to encourage employees to conduct research and development during their work time or spare time .
3. From among them , pick out 50 for submission to an assessment committee to assess .
Since the <LOCATION>Tangshan Earthquake</LOCATION> , the starting point for construction standards in the mainland is that under an earthquake of the same magnitude , buildings should preserve their basic frame without collapsing .
However , most of the buildings in this hard - hit area did not meet these requirements , with the widespread collapse of school buildings in particular arousing intense public disgust .
Raising standards to in excess of <LOCATION>Tangshan</LOCATION> 's 8.0 magnitude could leave authorities with some breathing space for explanation , and alleviate public anger .
According to information leaked from numerous channels , we can say for certain that before the earthquake struck , the serious earthquake risk in the <LOCATION>Ngawa</LOCATION> region was already well known to the <ORGANIZATION>CCP</ORGANIZATION> .
Although current forecasting standards cannot give us an accurate prediction of the exact time , place , and strength of an earthquake , there is considerable experience accumulated both in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and overseas in predicting to within the timeframe of a month , and the area of a province .
In regions where the earthquake risk is high , warning the public and spreading disaster prevention awareness could greatly reduce casualties during earthquakes ; this is the very minimum duty that any responsible government should undertake .
In the past the <ORGANIZATION>CCP</ORGANIZATION> has done a lot of these sorts of things , but on this occasion not only did nothing , but in response to queries from the public pulled out some whopping lies , playing syntax games with words like " geological disaster " and " earthquake disaster " .
I think that if our <ORGANIZATION>Earthquake Administration</ORGANIZATION> had been able beforehand to do a simulation of big earthquakes on this <LOCATION>Longmenshan</LOCATION> mountain earthquake belt , then on that day of <DATE>May 12</DATE> , once the <ORGANIZATION>Earthquake Administration</ORGANIZATION> had measured the quake at a magnitude of 7.8 , we would have been able to broadly judge the extent of damage and destruction in the earthquake disaster zone .
In addition , the breakdown in communication also brought a serious problem to the surface . In the past , <ORGANIZATION>Red Army</ORGANIZATION> regiments were able to maintain contact with central headquarters by relying on just one battered radio . On this occasion though , people had no way to deal with the communication failure .
It is clear that preparations prior to the event were not constructed on the basis of an earthquake disaster simulation .
While it should have been a disaster relief command that takes overall leadership , it has suddenly come face - to - face with the broad base of disaster victims , directly dealing with them .
This would have been unimaginable during the <ORGANIZATION>Great Tangshan Earthquake</ORGANIZATION> . A time without volunteers or mental workers , such petty things as directly dealing with average people were performed by the most primary Party branches , as well as enterprises and public institutions .
As soon as the earthquake occurred , grass - root organizations contacted their own people and average people also contacted their own systems or departments , in an interdependent manner .
Under the centralized leadership of higher - level organizations , everyone acted to make the rescue efforts very outstanding and successful , such that the <ORGANIZATION>Great Tangshan Earthquake</ORGANIZATION> , which happened just a few years ago , was forgotten all together in the subsequent reform and opening - up .
It is obvious that no social or political problems were left then , nor were sequelae that cause headaches to later generations .
During a time of prosperity and happiness , such a big earthquake suddenly struck .
Many people died , much property was destroyed , it was quite clearly a great disaster .
But it was not totally without benefits , and I believe that its greatest benefit was that it served to strip off the false benevolence that composed the outer skin of the elitists , the politicians , the capitalists , and exposed once and for all the rotten cannibalistic core within .
And an additional benefit was that many people who had been deluded came to their senses .
Temporarily laid aside these abstract things and avoided speaking at length , saying only a few details that left the elitists , the politicians and capitalists highly embarrassed .
The experts had just finished saying " Sacrificing yourself to help others is a foolish idea " , when the leaders had no choice but to call once again for selfless devotion .
This was mere chicanery , to the point where before engaging in life - saving , donation to charity , these sorts of behaviors , an idea had to be flashing through people 's minds :
Am I being foolish in doing this ?
And when people saw on <ORGANIZATION>CCTV</ORGANIZATION> those private firms manufacturing tents in <LOCATION>Jiangsu</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Zhejiang</LOCATION> working overtime to produce more tents , the first idea that popped to mind I 'm afraid was probably " This time these capitalists have struck it big ! "
" Why is it that these capitalists instead of those capitalists get the big order forms , surely there could n't be anything fishy involved ?
During this process , there were again talks about filing a complaint against the <ORGANIZATION>Xinghui Travel Agency</ORGANIZATION> .
The reason for filing the complaint is that even if we owed their hourly fees , they still should fulfill their obligation on the contract they signed : driving people from <LOCATION>Canberra</LOCATION> back to <LOCATION>Sydney</LOCATION> .
They even lied , saying that they and Xinghui initially felt that signing a contract would rather make each other feel like strangers since they were both doing it for the sake of the motherland .
As you know , this type of logic absolutely wo n't work in <LOCATION>Australia</LOCATION> .
Xinghui accepted this order of ours and deployed all the buses of other travel agencies in <LOCATION>Sydney</LOCATION> .
In addition , there was something else that was very suspicious .
I heard from a friend at the consulate that the government took this matter very seriously and had promptly agreed to allocate funds to compensate the students who had used their own money instead that night .
Yesterday afternoon I went back to check out the torch relay , but even the flame was practically impossible to see , let alone the guys carrying the torch .
There were so many people there it was frightening . Some had even climbed onto the roofs of buses !
I headed straight for the center of activities , but in actual fact traffic was being controlled as early as 4 o'clock , and they had already started limiting the crowds entering the sports center .
Some guys were really insane , banding together in groups and yelling out " Go <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> ! "
I actually had some other classmates there , and was going to call them .
I guessed the carrying capacity of the base station towers was totally overloaded , and I could n't get through at all . I was only able to find a signal , not a chance of connecting to the Internet .
Only one phone call I made there got through - that was calling home .
I had a look at my call register , and out of dozens of calls dialed only one was properly connected !
Sometime after 6 I went straight back home to watch it on TV . The spectacle was just as astonishing on TV , except that it was just one angle of the whole thing .
Next time I wo n't be partaking in this kind of activity !!
<PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> 's experience of being under public condemnation underscored to a certain extent the tense relationship between the rich and poor classes in Chinese society ;
because as <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> grows prosperous day by day , the gap of wealth between the successful elite and the remaining 1.3 billion people is widening .
However , Hurun Report ( Hurun Report ) shows that by <DATE>2007</DATE> , there were a total of 106 billionaires ( in <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> dollars ) in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , with the number of people only next to that of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> .
Now , <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> said , these responses have had effects on me .
<PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> noted additionally that since <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> currently has not yet established a sound system of social security insurance , the growing hatred of the rich is unavoidable .
On <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> , <PERSON>Wanke</PERSON> announced that it would make an additional donation of <ORGANIZATION>RMB</ORGANIZATION> <MONEY>100 million yuan</MONEY> for the temporary resettlement and post - disaster reconstruction in the next three to five years .
Yao Ming , the basketball player who was hailed as a national hero thanks to his success in establishing himself in <ORGANIZATION>NBA</ORGANIZATION> , was also blamed after he announced his donation of RMB two million yuan because a rumor on the Internet alleged he had donated <MONEY>one million U.S. dollars</MONEY> for disaster relief of Hurricane Katrina ( Hurricane ) in <DATE>2005</DATE> .
Even so , donation behavior and the treatment of donation behavior should not deviate from two principles , namely that it is voluntary and does not seek return . Otherwise , the donation loses its original meaning .
In actual fact , whether it is <ORGANIZATION>McDonalds</ORGANIZATION> or any other foreign owned enterprises in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> on the so - called " international iron rooster " blacklist , they all gave generously to the cause of helping the disaster victims , exhibiting their social responsibility .
Donating , after all , is not a legal obligation that companies must carry out . Urging businesses to donate apart from the force of moral considerations should not take the form of any other coercive means .
As long as a company 's source of income is legal , any compulsory payment outside of legal obligations is a kind of theft .
Even in an abnormal circumstance such as disaster relief , legal order and the rights bestowed upon by law should be respected .
If we are unfortunate enough to be unable to avoid becoming a disaster victim , we can at least preserve the nobility and dignity of humanity and not turn into rabble .
The lawsuit proposed by <PERSON>Hai Ming</PERSON> did not have a clear subject of the right of action ; moreover it did not satisfy the legal requirement for libel .
For example , he failed to clarify whether <PERSON>Cafferty</PERSON> 's comment was an argument over opinions or an act of spreading an untruthful statement .
The malicious intent of <PERSON>Cafferty</PERSON> has not been established , either . More importantly , he has been unable to offer anything as to how to establish the damage to the 1.3 billion Chinese people .
In addition , in his complaint , it is said that Chinese people have already expressed their displeasure through demonstrations .
Here it is a country with the freedom of speech .
On the issue of libel , courts only support those who have actually suffered damages and have no other way to seek justice .
Therefore , it is very hard for the government , politicians , and public figures to get legal protection on the issue of libel ,
because they have the capability to clear themselves of " smears . "
If you have already cleared your own reputation through legal protests , for example , Chinese people are not goons and thugs , then a lawsuit is meaningless .
Remember , a lawsuit for libel is only to clear your name and get compensation .
After <PERSON>Lee Teng</PERSON> - hui put forth the " two states theory " , due to mainland countrymen being deceived by the <ORGANIZATION>CCP</ORGANIZATION> 's propaganda machine , many people advocated using force to unite <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> .
Because they have no understanding whatsoever of the situation in <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> and the will of the <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> people ,
hey universally exhibited extreme nationalistic sentiment .
Just like the love - hate fusion of nationalistic war sentiment that erupted after the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> mistakenly bombed the Chinese embassy .
They similarly did not understand the real story in <LOCATION>Kosovo</LOCATION> .
But <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> people realize that first there was the Republic of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , only after that came " <LOCATION>New China</LOCATION> " ;
While this " Two States Separatist Theory " has purely and simply been dreamed up by the <ORGANIZATION>CCP</ORGANIZATION> .
Lee Teng - hui was doing nothing but bringing an already existing phenomenon to light .
However , even though <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> people have their grumbles , the " two states theory " has in no way triggered a sentimental attachment in <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> people for " Old <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> " .
I believe that our building industry here has not yet reached this level .
Not only has the law not yet reached this level , but the average person 's understanding has generally not reached this level .
Some officials , out of local economic considerations , by accident or design are frequently too lenient in dealing with property agents .
We all saw the damage wreaked by the <ORGANIZATION>Wenchuan Earthquake</ORGANIZATION> .
As to how much of this was a result of natural disaster , and how much was man - made calamity , a verdict will be drawn in the end .
Apparently , quality checks in the space industry are extremely rigorous , each part undergoes several inspection processes , every effort is made to ensure absolute safety .
But space ship accidents still happen from time to time .
Even such technologically advanced nations as the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> have experienced several instances of space flight launch or return failures .
Since things can still go wrong even when they are subjected to incredibly rigorous inspections as in the space industry , then , with our current " dark " and corrupt property industry the way it is , people 's lives are even harder to place guarantees on .
Once a powerful earthquake strikes , the people 's lives really do become as tiny as those of ants .
It makes one tremble even without fear .
Following the <LOCATION>Great Wenchuan Earthquake</LOCATION> this time , there were compatriots who struggled out of the debris , wiped their tears and buried the bodies of their families , but they braced up again and declared to the world , " we are not beaten down ; we are on our feet again ; the earthquake cannot shake the staunch will of the Chinese people ; trials and tribulations serve only to revitalize a nation ! "
This enables us to see the fighting spirits of the dauntless Chinese nation give off a dazzling radiance among people in disaster - hit areas .
The fact that these words are spoken by compatriots who have been through the disaster has given us , who could n't help our tears at the sight of their mishaps , so much comfort and encouragement . It gives us a hint that no force can beat down the Chinese people .
I just want to say , let there be no more disasters , so that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is safe and sound from now on and disasters are far away from <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
I pray to the God to open his eyes and do n't let disasters visit the Chinese land again !
One important reason that a great number of people buried or trapped in debris in the <LOCATION>Wenchuan</LOCATION> earthquake - hit area were saved is that they were full of hopes and firmly believed the <ORGANIZATION>PLA</ORGANIZATION> would come to their rescue !
Tens of thousands or even millions of those displaced by the disaster have gradually had a home to shelter from the wind and rain !
If everything were put in the market , such that all the land was sold to syndicates or farm owners , then where should the government set up tents ?
Do they expropriate the land on the spot ?
Even the government cannot override the market !
If everything were put in the market , such that workers and farmers would have their fates controlled by the market and no longer count on or rely on the government by walking onto a path of the so - called " finding the market rather than the mayor ( government ) , " then what power would the government have ?
The post - catastrophe hyperinflation as expected by foreigners has not come either !
The government has human and financial capital under control , as well as energy and resources !
For example , the value of " seizing the pleasure of the moment " also has a long history .
" Sing a song when thou have wine , seize the day since life is short . " Some people in contemporary times think we should " satisfy and die . "
Some people have gone so far on the road that they " do n't know how to eat or play , "
and other take nude pictures and flaunt them online .
For another example , the pursuit of office titles and levels can also be traced back to the old days .
In ancient times there was <PERSON>Zhou Li</PERSON> to distinguish the order of hierarchy and nobility , constructing a pyramid - like social organizational structure .
The aim was to settle disputes , stop fights and stabilize the society .
However , simultaneously it has also established a system that values life according to office levels , which to the contrary triggered contentions and destabilized the society .
Higher or lower ranks in Qing Dynasty were distinguished by bird and animal patterns on clothes , <LOCATION>Taiping Heavenly Kingdom</LOCATION> used the size and color of a sedan chair as the symbol to distinguish between different ranks , and modern people use the motor vehicle displacement as a symbol to distinguish between different positions , all of which can be traced to the same origin .
I do n't care how much <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> wastes every time he climbs a mountain , but I do strongly despise how he talks and the way he acts during this whole thing .
After donating , he suggested that charity should not be the burden of businesses , and therefore stipulated that his company 's employee donations should not exceed 10 yuan .
Totally absurd logic . <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> 's reasoning is that making donations to charities then the burden of businesses could cause companies to fail in market competition ;
And there were some netizens who hit back in the <ORGANIZATION>Wang Shi</ORGANIZATION> donations issue by admonishing us for forcing donations on moral grounds .
Exactly ! An excellent justification !
If you say that netizens rebuking <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> is forcing donations , then what kind of behavior is <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> preventing employees from donating more than 10 yuan ?
<PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> is the economic version of a cold - blooded animal , and we do n't care ,
but how come <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> , how come he wants to restrict what employees do or do n't do on moral grounds ?
This really is a case of one rule for some , another rule for everyone else !!!
We see , as at <DATE>May 17</DATE> , the Chinese government has accepted up to <MONEY>6 billion</MONEY> in disaster - relief donations domestically and internationally , of which 4.8 billion is from domestic donors .
What we can see now are merely the name and figure of each donor constantly listed in what is like an honor roll .
Yet unfortunately , we do n't have more detailed information of the whereabouts and specific uses of the donated funds .
As corruption has long been prevalent among local governments and economic auditing is not transparent enough , disaster - relief funds are often appropriated , exhausted , expropriated and embezzled .
Therefore , once such a huge amount of disaster - relief funds from people the world and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> are embezzled or otherwise partially transferred by local officials , the resulting political damage and lowering of the government 's image domestically and internationally will completely negate the positive image brought by the government 's disaster - relief efforts .
If the donations are directly put in the hands of disaster - hit people , it would push local prices higher , driving the already high inflation to a direction that is even harder to regulate .
So , we again hear expert figures emphasizing once again , " Earthquake forecasts are a global challenge that so far no one has been able to solve . "
We should offer earthquake workers our full understanding .
Facing the caprice of nature , <LOCATION>humankind</LOCATION> is really insignificant .
Furthermore , although our sense of security increases with each passing day in line with " significant advances achieved " in seismology , we cannot look to anyone to give us any promises .
And by not issuing any promises , he could actually avoid being censured .
Because " there is no way to make predictions " !
Do not regard earthquake prediction as a " practical skill " ; rather regard it as academic work in a study .
Take no notice of the real results in terms of preventing earthquakes or minimizing disasters ; rather singlemindedly pursue the scientific research level embodied in " prediction success rates . "
In the course of major disaster warnings , too many disputes relating to powers and interests are entangled .
The directions of research into earthquake prevention and disaster minimization are just confined to research into the phenomenon of earthquakes , but efforts to intervene in urban construction , to formulate and supervise building standards , and perfect and improve disaster rescue mechanisms and other aspects have been neglected .... .
We have also become blindly abreast of foreign countries even in earthquake research : we do n't believe in living beings raised as part of nature ; we just believe in the instruments we ourselves manufacture .
We do n't believe the warnings sent out by nature ; we just believe the warnings emitted by instruments in laboratories .
We do n't believe in what is seen and heard with their own eyes by millions of ordinary people ; we just believe in the authoritative conclusions of experts and scholars .
Chinese seismology is galloping down the wrong road .
Real estate is only one part of the national economy but the real estate phenomenon exists in every sector of the national economy .
The swift large - scale failure and bankruptcy of collective enterprises and state - owned enterprises is proof of this .
We should n't be too bothered if folks like <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> say something unpleasant .
A defeated general ca n't claim to be brave .
In front of folks like <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> , the <ORGANIZATION>State Council</ORGANIZATION> are all defeated generals .
Because the missing - in - action army who built <LOCATION>New China</LOCATION> have been beaten to a pulp by folks like <PERSON>Wang Shi</PERSON> ; even if <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has no earthquakes , there will be floods , as well as SARS , snowstorms , big freezes etc.
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is a land of many catastrophes - this has always been true and always will be .
Relying on singing for donations , entertaining for one 's <DATE>supper</DATE> , will not solve the problem .
And time and time again asking the national television station to get out there and carry the national flag , carrying on like this in the name of the country is outrageous , it 's the <ORGANIZATION>State Council</ORGANIZATION> 's problem .
All the people with one mind " as the national anthem is inspired by the foresight of " always being prepared " , designed for " advance , advance , advance , enter ! " instead of being designed for repeated begging , pleading for donations , and fund - raising .
From leaders to the common people , everyone needs to keep that in mind .
When we go back to the <ORGANIZATION>10th Century AD</ORGANIZATION> , we find that the 10th Century AD gave birth to the first entrepreneurs .
Because the 10th Century AD was the very time when limited liability companies were established ; the Catholic Pope of the time had such a conviction during the <ORGANIZATION>9th Century</ORGANIZATION> .
Are you afraid of going to Hell when you die ?
Yes , you are afraid - how could you not go just because you are afraid ?
Donate your property to the Church , show your loyalty to God and you wo n't go to Hell ,
so a lot of rich people donated their money to the <ORGANIZATION>Church</ORGANIZATION> before they died .
By the <ORGANIZATION>10th Century AD</ORGANIZATION> , <PERCENT>60 %</PERCENT> of <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> 's territory belonged to the Church ,
but their clergymen could n't manage it , and were unable to pass it on to the next generation . What could they do ?
So they set up the modern limited liability company .
How did they set it up ?
They hired professional managers to run these Church enterprises ,
hese professional managers were the administrators ,
And who were the proprietors of these companies ?
The Church .
So what did this confirm ?
The first step in separating the administration rights from ownership ,
in no way because this was a great system , but rather that this was inevitable within the Church enterprises .
When forecasting earthquakes , why did it happen that only a few cases were successful while most cases were failures ?
According to this writer 's many years of research on precursory signs , the existence of precursory signs and earthquake predictions are two issues that are both connected and mutual differentiated .
The appearance of a precursory sign does n't mean it can accurately forecast the three elements of an earthquake , because precursory signs are extremely complicated .
There are certain differences in the categories , breadths , distribution ranges , and duration of precursory signs of different types of earthquakes in different places .
In " Regional Nature of Precursory Signs of Earthquakes , " this writer divides earthquakes into two major types according to the overall characteristics of pre - earthquake signs : strike - type and slip - type earthquakes .
The former occurs in areas where internal fault blocks or fault lines converge but not intersect , while the latter occurs in active fault lines .
Strike - type earthquakes have various types of precursory signs , which are widespread , long - lasting , and quite variable .
Slip - type earthquakes have fewer types of precursory signs , which have a smaller distribution range , shorter duration period , and smaller range of change .
In <LOCATION>Chengdu</LOCATION> , which is over 100 kms away from the epicenter , the earthquake should not have an intensity of over 7 , or 8 at the most .
There should not be any safety problems for Class A buildings like those at the airport , hospitals and schools that are designed to withstand a intensity of 8 .
So most buildings in <LOCATION>Chengdu</LOCATION> should still be able to use after emergency assessment , and citizens may go home reassured .
If large sums of money have been spent to provide protection , yet it fails to work when the earthquake comes ,
such that nobody dares to live at home , is able to use hospitals , or accesses airports , then has the money been thrown for nothing ?
Probably some would say the national building criteria for earthquake resistance was enacted in recent years , and older buildings may not comply with the requirements .
However , at the same time the government enacted the earthquake resistance criteria , it required all existing buildings which did not satisfy the criteria to be reinforced and removed of dangers in a timely fashion .
Thus one cannot shirk responsibilities on excuse that it is an old building .
In addition , the government also has criteria for earthquake resistance and prevention for rural buildings .
The earthquake in <LOCATION>Sichuan</LOCATION> stuns everyone .
Elementary school buildings collapsed , and children were buried in the rubble .
Middle school buildings collapsed , and young students were buried under the crumbled walls .
Kindergarten buildings also collapsed , and little children 's frail bodies fell helplessly next to the crumbled walls where they closed their innocent eyes forever .
We could n't help crying at this sorrowful scene .
Children are the flowers of our motherland and future of our motherland .
These flowers of life died early in a natural disaster .
Natural disasters cannot be predicted , but the school buildings should not have collapsed .
Why are the buildings behind the school buildings still there while the school buildings where children studied collapsed from the first floor to the fourth floor leaving only crumbled walls ?
Children , you should n't have departed like this .
Every year , all levels of People 's <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> are held from local governments to the <ORGANIZATION>Central Government</ORGANIZATION> .
Deputies to the People 's <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> , please make an all - around inspection of school buildings in all areas and inspect whether or not the school buildings in your constituencies are up to local earthquake - resistance standards , and then quickly make a proposal according to the existing problems and push each level of the government to complete rectifications and improvements within a limited time .
Special legislation in the <ORGANIZATION>National People 's Congress</ORGANIZATION> on construction of school buildings should be proposed .
There needs to be special legal procedures for the design , materials , construction , completion , and inspection of the school buildings to ensure that top priority be given to quality and durability .
Allowing all children to study safely is the sacred and bounden duty of the People 's <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> .
In <DATE>June 1976</DATE> , 83 year - old <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> had already been revived once after suffering a myocardial infarction .
To get effective care for his condition , the <ORGANIZATION>Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CCP</ORGANIZATION> established a special treatment team , in charge of his medical treatment and care .
The <ORGANIZATION>Political Bureau</ORGANIZATION> also specifically assigned people to the task of <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> 's medical care , taking turns with the doctors and nurses to be on constant vigil at his living quarters .
On the day of the <LOCATION>Tangshan Earthquake</LOCATION> , i.e. <DATE>July 28th</DATE> , those on duty at <LOCATION>Mao Zedong</LOCATION> 's quarters were <ORGANIZATION>Wang Dongxing</ORGANIZATION> , <PERSON>Wang Hongwen</PERSON> , and <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> 's confidential secretary , <PERSON>Zhang Yufeng</PERSON> .
In the early hours of the morning , with the clock hands pointing to 3:42 , the ground of <LOCATION>Zhongnanhai</LOCATION> suddenly started to shudder .
While <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> was convalescing , the employees and medical staff around him were all in a state of high tension , maintaining extremely silent surroundings and atmosphere .
In normal times , apart from the talking and noise of medical instruments when the doctors revived him , not a whisper could be heard .
After the nineties , state - owned engineering enterprises stopped recruiting construction workers .
A collision occurred between tradition and reality .
Due to formal working units no longer taking on young employees , working units got increasingly older and broken up .
Some staff ( extremely few ) entered management .
A few exceptional former team leaders gradually became project managers .
Others became materials officers , safety officers and quality control officers , etc.
Those without connections became staff monitoring the construction site ------ similar to the security guards of today .
The workers no longer formed complete operating teams .
The entire on - site operation work was all carried out by contracting gangs .
Working units disbanded .
The status of these workers was also changing .
In each case of corruption , those power - wielding bureaucrats , those scholars or technicians who have cornered the market in their fields , those capitalists with vast wealth , they are the ruling force of this society , and also the ones who profit from the corruption .
The powerless , pennyless working public with no access to information technology resources % PW are the ones who lose out from the corruption .
Today 's society is corrupt in every direction , and the direct cause is the reinstatement of private ownership and the scrapping of the public supervision of the <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> era .
In privatized societies , everybody tramples over others trying to maximize their own interests .
Doctors who do n't receive ' red envelopes ' have no motivation to properly cure the patient .
Teachers openly ask students to give them gifts ,
gang ringleaders use cash to have the media make them out as heroes ,
capitalists trying to annex state - owned property team up with scholars and academically demonstrate state - owned monopolies to be the reason behind corruption , and then reap in the profits .
Frequently the public , under the guidance of the mainstream media , only concern themselves with administrative and judicial corruption ; this in itself is a type of corruption .
<DATE>December 26 , 1975</DATE> , <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> had his 82th birth day , his last one .
Upon turning 80 , <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> felt apparently that he was old and would die soon .
One thing he often said was : " 73 and 84 are ages at which you will be gone even if the <ORGANIZATION>King of Hell</ORGANIZATION> does n't call you . "
Within the country , people dared not celebrate his birthday publicly , so they would celebrate quietly at home .
Local governments dared not present gifts to <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> , but would convey their blessings to <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> in various ways .
In the years before <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> passed away , his hometown Hunan would specially send things like long life noodles on <DATE>December 26</DATE> every year .
For this , <PERSON>Mao Zedong</PERSON> had accepted with pleasure , which was quite unusual .
Despite <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> 's status as the globe 's most financially endowed high - tech leader , bargaining with <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> is something that is sure to leave you greatly disillusioned .
<ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> 's dictionary has never contained the word " generous " .
So when the <PERSON>Jerry Yangs</PERSON> hope that by bargaining they can bump up <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> 's purchase price , they are being very unrealistic .
Microsoft raising its price ever so slightly already represented a big concession , proving that it really does want to get its hands on <ORGANIZATION>Yahoo</ORGANIZATION> ! .
Ultimately choosing to give it up was obviously a very painful decision for <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION> .
Right from the start , this was a super acquisition that lacked bite ; despite the numbers being huge , even if the acquisition was successful , truly revolutionizing the framework of the Internet was simply not possible .
However , when the acquisition did fall through , it was also quite disappointing .
To us global observers watching the bustling scene , giving up the acquisition was like a play stopped abruptly halfway through , without ever getting the chance to watch the rest of the fun , and indeed there was no shortage of theatrical transformations .
We have no choice but to return back to our mundane lives , and wait for this increasingly passion - destroying industry to come up with the next affair of note .
Since last <DATE>September</DATE> , when his daughter was diagnosed with symptoms such as bloody feces and kidney stones , <PERSON>Zhou Jin</PERSON> has been in succession to Yongzhou in <LOCATION>Hunan</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Hebei</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Xiamen</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Guangzhou</LOCATION> , and more to take his daughter to hospitals for treatment , but the child 's illness has continued to improve and decline .
This <DATE>September</DATE> , <PERSON>Zhou Jin</PERSON> , working in <LOCATION>Shenzhen</LOCATION> , took his daughter to the <ORGANIZATION>Shenzhen Children 's Hospital</ORGANIZATION> for examination and treatment .
The results of the examination are that the upper rectum was severely infected and the right kidney expanded . The kidney stone found in previous hospital treatments was not found this time .
<PERSON>Zhou Jin</PERSON> said that his daughter , a little over two years old this year , had eaten <ORGANIZATION>Sanlu</ORGANIZATION> milk powder for over a year . Last <DATE>September</DATE> after the bloody feces appeared , family members took his daughter to the Yongzhou hospital for examination . The doctors informed them that " there is no better treatment method , just have her drink more water . "
Worrying about his daughter 's illness , <PERSON>Zhou Jin</PERSON> asked the county hospital to issue a certificate to transfer her to another hospital , to let his daughter go to a better hospital for treatment .
The hospital <ORGANIZATION>Medical Administration Department</ORGANIZATION> told <PERSON>Zhou Jin</PERSON> that issuing of the certificate to transfer to another hospital would require the approval of <ORGANIZATION>the Ministry of Health</ORGANIZATION> , and more than one month would be needed .
" I went repeatedly to find the relevant health department , but they passed my case back and forth . I was helpless and could only take my daughter to the place where I work -- <LOCATION>Xiamen</LOCATION> , to carry out treatment . "
Have to suffer this pain .
The doctor in charge told us that the kid would be out of danger if he could just urinate .
Getting him to urinate could n't be more difficult !
This urine is more valuable than gold .
He did n't pee at all during the first two or three days in hospital .
We were all desperate at that time .
The hospital already arranged for him to undergo dialysis surgery .
And my satisfying son finally urinated .
Out of danger at last , but one trouble passed and another one took its place , there came an acute diarrhea and fever , he was stooling several dozen times every day , you can imagine the suffering .
He had just danced a circle around the Grim Reaper , and encounted this problem on top of that . I was really worried he would n't pull through .
I do n't know what was happening with the injection treatment at the hospital - the more they injected him the worse the diarrhea , nothing would stop it .
After a few more days of treatment , the kid 's diarrhea was a little better and the doctors got him to do an ultrasound .
The kidney stone had been washed out by the medicine . There were no more stones on his kidneys .
The hospitalization was very expensive and our family could n't afford it , so we had no choice but to leave the hospital and go home .
On the night of <ORGANIZATION>Dragon Boat Festival</ORGANIZATION> he passed out a stone by himself , it was a sedimentary one .
The whole family was really excited , we all thought he was better , that he was cured .
On the day of <DATE>September 1st</DATE> alone , at the entrance of " Longyuan Supermarket " on <LOCATION>Urumqi</LOCATION> 's Friendship Road , two people were injected and sent to hospital .
On the same day , in <LOCATION>Shuimogou District</LOCATION> , No. 106 Bus had just pulled up at the Gaojiazhuang stop when several people were injected , soon , the Uyghur assailants jumped from the bus and fled , but they were soon detained after bystanders gave chase .
The 920 and many other buses also experienced a number of poisoned syringe cases .
On <DATE>August 31</DATE> , the No. 17 bus exploded near <LOCATION>Xibei Road</LOCATION> , while the No. 14 bus was bombed at the same time .
Nevertheless , all news was blocked .
But witnesses shortly after spread the news to the outside world by telephone - <LOCATION>Urumqi</LOCATION> security is extremely deteriorating !
Even more ironic was in <DATE>late August</DATE> , when * President <PERSON>Hu Jintao</PERSON> * had just visited <LOCATION>Xinjiang</LOCATION> on an inspection tour . Upon his return to <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> , the situation in <LOCATION>Urumqi</LOCATION> was far from settling , instead the * Uyghur terrorists * becoming even more rampant , and the numbers of attacks and bombings were increasing rather than decreasing !
The incompetence of the <LOCATION>Xinjiang</LOCATION> government would make the Central extremely troublesome !
After so many years can they still sing Yesterday Once More ?
Dear friends , let me fill in some of the words for the melody right now in my heart .
Do n't worry , the cold - blood is n't me , it 's a part of my heart .
If an Olympic Games were held taking the damage done to mankind by industrial pollution as theme , I think our dear motherland should be able to win a gold medal and a champion of winning the grand total in gold medals . I just do n't know how the opening ceremony would be run , how volunteers should be recruited , or which song should be sung lustily .
The title of the sick man of <LOCATION>East Asia</LOCATION> once went far away following the revolutionary course brimming with victories , but after seeing this group of photos , I feel that they have whistled back with this brand new attitude of faster , higher , stronger .
What is different is that I dare not expect for ; in what way can we have again " The Destruction of Opium at <LOCATION>Humen</LOCATION> " with " upholding the country 's interests with one 's life " .
Because we and our motherland cannot depart from this shocking pollution . What we can do is just to improve , adjust and vaguely hope .
At that time , tens of thousands of city youth headed to the countryside , but by no means were all of them were true believers .
Some were under pressure to show their " revolutionary zeal " , others went because there were no jobs in the city .
The poverty and backwardness of the countryside were appalling , and most of the educated youth became disillusioned .
In the middle of the <DATE>1970</DATE> 's the intensity of the Cultural Revolution waned , and one after one the youths returned to the cities or went to study in university , but back then there was n't an exam to get into university , it depended on your political background and behavior .
Jianguo was not one of these . He worked for seven years in a rural part of Inner <LOCATION>Mongolia</LOCATION> , became a village head , and was very popular with the locals .
He was a dab hand at working the fields , and could match the locals when it came to drinking spirits .
Although the villagers had no interest in the various kinds of " revolutionary practices " that Jianguo tried to make them adopt , he was honest and kind , and his generous personality won their friendship and affection .
After <PERSON>Jianguo</PERSON> had returned to <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> for not even a few moths , the student movement in <LOCATION>Tiananmen</LOCATION> began .
Twenty years before , the god of the " Red Guards " was Mao , but the ideal of young people now was wearing jeans and a T - shirt , and a new statue had been erected : Lady Liberty .
At that time I lived in <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> , and every day went to the square . When we ran into each other , <PERSON>Jianguo</PERSON> did n't say much . However it looked like he had a million thoughts stirring in his heart .
One afternoon , I went to see an active figure in the square , and arranged to go together with him .
Jianguo was just behind me and had just started to come inside , when my friends frowned and stopped him : " No , you ca n't come inside ! "
I explained , saying this was my brother . My friends listened with surprise .
Wang Peirong thinks that this is related to blockages in the usual reporting channels .
He pointed out , all of his reports were made under the circumstances that the normal reports did n't work , and he had no choice but made reports online .
A typical example is that the fall of <ORGANIZATION>Dong Feng</ORGANIZATION> , the most debaucherous secretary labeled as one - husband - with - two - wife in the country .
Wang Peirong thinks that <ORGANIZATION>Dong Feng</ORGANIZATION> 's absurdity and corruption was actually an open secret , but nobody investigated and penalized ; and even though <PERSON>Wang Peirong</PERSON> reported on this using his real name to the concerned departments for one year , no one bothered to inquire about it .
Wang Peirong also thinks that reporting online is equivalent to publicizing the corruptive deeds of the person being reported against . Once under the public eye , the possibility of any blatant cover - <ORGANIZATION>ups</ORGANIZATION> becomes greatly reduced , thus , making it easier to investigate and penalize .
There are likely three original reasons why 360 uses a person 's name to issue Chargeback Rival :
General manager <PERSON>Zhou</PERSON> has done too much bad stuff on PC 's , and did n't want to offend too many people on cell phones , so he found an individual author to act as a scapegoat ( if a cell phone SP company knew that it was 360 that block their way . Each one of them is tough . ) ;
Using an individual author to issue it , it was easy to defraud the grassroots netizens of their sense of identification and sympathy .
If you see I am an individual netizen , who has been charged money , so makes a piece of software in order to help everyone solve this problem , then how moved it seems from the outside .
Using an individual author to issue , there has been a strong power of captivation . Many companies in the SP and wireless realm would definitely think that a product from an individual author would not have much influence , so would not pay too much attention to it .
Nevertheless , 360 already did this under cover of promoting <ORGANIZATION>Chargeback Rival</ORGANIZATION> in large scale . Once after <ORGANIZATION>Chargeback Rival</ORGANIZATION> became dominant on the situation , then it is to be transformed into 360 .
Having seen no hope from <ORGANIZATION>Xu Ming</ORGANIZATION> , <PERSON>Wang Peirong</PERSON> then could only post the relevant problems online .
But these have not been able to halt the momentum of <ORGANIZATION>Wang Peirong</ORGANIZATION> 's reporting .
However , in the program , <PERSON>Wang Peirong</PERSON> calls out to the parties and the government to set out policies and provisions to protect the personal safety and legal rights of whistle blowers .
This program of <ORGANIZATION><< News Night Banquet</ORGANIZATION> >> on <LOCATION>Jiangsu</LOCATION> TV 's city channel , caused a great uproar in the community .
But in contrast with this , <PERSON>Wang Peirong</PERSON> , well reputed as <LOCATION>Jiangsu</LOCATION> 's " number one person in online anti - corruption " , is now suffering unfair treatment .
How <ORGANIZATION>China University of Mining and Technology</ORGANIZATION> responds to <LOCATION>Jiangsu</LOCATION> mainstream media 's positive and active appraisal of Wang Peirong ; how well they treat Wang Peirong ; and how they protect <PERSON>Wang Peirong</PERSON> 's legal rights , are unavoidable questions placed in front of the <ORGANIZATION>Mining University</ORGANIZATION> 's decision makers .
The Chinese defense budget for <DATE>2012</DATE> is RMB 670.274 billion , increasing by RMB 67.604 billion and <PERCENT>11.2 %</PERCENT> compared to the previous year 's estimated budgetary expenditure .
The Chinese military expenditures are increasing too fast for <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , and the increase is currently over RMB 100 billion , but what on earth can <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> do with this additional amount of more than <MONEY>RMB 100 billion dollars</MONEY> ?
Based on the current exchange rate between the Renminbi and <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> dollar , it amounts to more than <MONEY>US$ 10 billion</MONEY> , which can purchase more than a hundred of the latest 3.5 generation Western fighter planes .
If it is used to manufacture Chinese J - 10 fighters , over two hundred planes can be produced , or perhaps even more . In one go , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> can improve its prowess in the air by a margin even greater than the total sum of a mid - sized Western country .
In fact , what <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> really fears is not the increase of military expenditure , but rather the rapid rate at which <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is upgrading its military technologies , which may enable <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to overtake <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> soon .
Compared to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has many inadequacies , for instance , its high technology development is not as mature as <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 's , and its basic infrastructure , the standard of education of its citizens , development of its systems and so on are also lacking . However , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has its own natural advantages , and that is <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> possesses a long history and stability of culture .
Some people pointed out in their comments that this is a serious disadvantage to <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> when compared to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , as they say that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is carrying too heavy a burden which will hinder rapid development ,
in fact , this reasoning is extremely incorrect , the Chinese culture is profound , so whatever problems the country may face , it can draw on its historic experiences ,
for instance , when <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> deals with international affairs , it can learn from how the Yuan Dynasty handled foreign trade and the problems of co - existence between multiple ethnic groups , or it could at least draw a lesson from the negative experiences .
Currently <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is drastically cutting down on its military expenditure , however it fears that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> will substantially increase its military expenditure . America is desperately attempting to return to the <LOCATION>Pacific Ocean</LOCATION> as it wishes to continue to contain the growth of Chinese military strength ,
<LOCATION>America</LOCATION> controls the Straits of <LOCATION>Malacca</LOCATION> , and a large majority of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's shipping vessels are under its control . However if <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> wishes to maintain the development of world trade order , its expenses will naturally be enormous .
If it were not for the financial crisis , a number of Western countries have stated that they would not have considered budgetary issues for American military deployments .
As a matter of fact , neighboring countries need not be too sensitive to the sharp increase in Chinese military spending . They fear that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> will pose a direct threat to them , but Chinese history has shown that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has never had the habit of wielding its military might to challenge Western countries , but as for how they habitually view <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> will depend on the profound influence of the Chinese culture .
China does not like to show off , preferring to restrain itself , and the same is true in the field of military matters .
Up to now , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> revealed that it has three models of the 4th generation stealth fighter planes under research and development , and the J 20 is expected to enter mass production and service next year , which is a direct blow to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> ,
however , what is even more terrifying for <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is that this Chinese fighter plane model has already displayed surprisingly advanced performance during combat , and it is feared that its level of technological advancement cannot be matched by the F 22. After all , this model of fighter plane has never participated in actual inspections up to this point .
Perhaps this is understandable for <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , but it is inevitable that the 4th generation Chinese fighter plane would create a stir .
The original order has been disrupted . After all , the Chinese fighter is no less powerful than the American one .
Of course there is a strong possibility that this number has been greatly exaggerated , and it is also embellished by the <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> Threat theory . However , such moves by <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> no longer has much effect on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , even if the Chinese defense expenditures reach <MONEY>US$ 200 billion</MONEY> , <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> cannot do anything to <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> ,
Recently , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> adopted an aggressive stance , casting negative votes on the <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> issue three times , and in relation to <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> 's naming of the <LOCATION>Diaoyu Islands</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> appears to be sending a message that ' we have accumulated sufficient power , and we are not afraid of your distortions of the truth . '
The Chinese military expenditures are soaring . By contrast , <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is continuously cutting down on its military expenditures , repeatedly asserting that its prowess will be replaced by small but elite troops that will not affect its capabilities . As it is nothing more than self - consolation , therefore , it caused widespread concern throughout <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> .
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's soaring military expenditures imply that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is reluctant to be limited to a position as the world 's No. 2 , and nor is it content to be world No. 1 in name only . Instead , it intends to recover its historical 1,500 - year glory as the leader of the world .
The content is not quite the same as the title ...
Let me whisper this : Doing business in <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> depends on connections , and red packets are also accepted ~ same as in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> ... :)
Faced with rascals and hooligans like the Americans , the Chinese have no choice but to arm themselves .
Indeed . I wonder what our military expenditure is like in proportion to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 's , and besides how much of our military expenditure is genuinely spent on sophisticated national defenses , if it is really spent on advanced defenses , there will never be such a thing as too much ! Compared to <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> we are still lagging far behind !
Now that Vice President Xi has visited <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , the direction for the Sino - American relationship has become the focus of world attention .
But no matter how sweetly imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> talks , I have no hope for imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has always been a country failing to live up to its words , and as long as something is in its interests , it will spare no effort and use any means to get it .
The relationship between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is like that between the sheep and the wolf , and do n't expect the wolf to change its ambition ,
he wolf and the sheep can never be friends , even if so , it 's only an illusion on our part , it 's only a wolf in sheep 's clothing .
Ultimately , it will reveal its wolf nature , and I hope the sheep will not be fooled by it .
The whole world expects <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> to coexist peacefully , jointly preside over and deal with international affairs , and build a peaceful new international order .
The peaceful coexistence of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is also the common wish of the people in the two countries .
Nevertheless , the peace we aspire to will be only our good wish .
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is the fallen petals that have the intention , but imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is the heartless flowing water .
Maintaining friendly relations with imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is only the wishful thinking of some Chinese !
Though there is a great distance between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and there are no territorial disputes , unlike our relationship with the <ORGANIZATION>Polar Bear</ORGANIZATION> , there is a direct conflict of interest .
However , due to ideological difference between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and the lack of the necessary trust and communication in handling international affairs , it is particularly imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , in its effort to contain the development of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and its threat to its hegemonic position , that makes trouble wherever possible to constrain the takeoff of the Chinese dragon .
Actually , imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has the initiative in terms of whether the two major countries , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> can get along ,
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has done a lot , and sacrificed a lot , for the Sino - American relationship ,
ut of its wishful thinking , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> uses its warm face to caress the cold ass of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , but it is still unable to win imperialistic <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 's sincerity , causing the Sino - American relationship to waver and even fall backwards .
In future times , as <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> challenges its world hegemony and imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> attempts to retain it , more clashes will happen , conflicts will be inevitable , and the struggle will become ever more ferocious .
In recent years , as <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's reform and opening - up campaign has reached greater depths , the people 's living standards have improved substantially , and its defense and military strength has also developed rapidly .
The status of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> as a major world power has begun to be more prominent , and in dealing with and directing international affairs , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has played an ever more important role .
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's rapid growth and rise has gradually threatened and challenged the hegemonic position of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> .
This makes imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> restless , and it has devised every possible means to contain and check <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's development .
Imperialist America wants to upset and restrain <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> with its military sales to <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> and the <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> issue !
The <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> issue has become an everlasting sorrow in the hearts of all descendants of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Imperialist America wants to control the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> and suppress <LOCATION>Syria</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> mainly because it covets the important strategic location and abundant resources of the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> .
Imperialist America wants to overthrow the Bashar regime to get rid of the Polar Bear 's only military base in the <LOCATION>Middle East !</LOCATION> It does not want the influence of the Polar Bear to exist in the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> region over the long term .
Imperialist America wants to topple <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> mainly to take on <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , to control <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's resources and contain <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's development .
In addition , it also wants to suppress the Polar Bear and squeeze the living space of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> .
In today 's world , the only countries that can constitute a threat to the hegemonic position of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> are <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and , to a lesser degree , the Polar Bear .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has had far - reaching strategic foresight , and each step it takes serves to consolidate its hegemony .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is suppressing <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> in an all - round way , and we can see imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> 's meddling presence in the economy , politics and military affairs .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has been supporting little <LOCATION>Japan</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> , the Philippine servants and the Vietnamese monkeys , disturbing the stable environment around <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to disrupt the peaceful development and rise of <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is now pompously returning to the <LOCATION>Asia Pacific</LOCATION> region and reshuffling its military deployment , directly targeting <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
<LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> is the deepest pain for all Chinese , because imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has long taken <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> as a pawn and used it as a bargaining chip in the struggle with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Furthermore , the many strategic adjustments and ideas of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> are all aimed at the rising <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Many advanced weapons have been tailor - made for <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Compatriots ! Wake up ! Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has already aimed its guns to our heads , do not keep daydreaming !
Imperialist America takes <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> as its prime rival and enemy , give up your fantasy that you can make friends with the enemy !
The best method is to make good use of our time to step up our own defense and military construction , cast away all the illusions , and get ready for war !
Our ancestors wisely said , " Harbor no ill intention against others , but never relax one 's vigilance " !
This is the necessary psychology for getting along with friends , but at this moment imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is our enemy staring like a tiger watching its prey , making it more necessary for us to remain vigilant at this time !
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has made a lot of sacrifices to improve its relations with imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has all along tried to become friends with imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> ,
although <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> now needs a peaceful and stable environment for its development , we ca n't make continual investments without any return .
Can Sino - American relations be improved ? Is friendly development possible ? The key question lies with imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , not <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has always held the initiative in the development of Sino - American relations .
In fact , it is not difficult for <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> to become friends , because <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , despite their ideological differences , have no land or territorial disputes .
Though <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> have fought each other on the battlefield , the wars were not directly between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> .
If imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> sincerely wants to make friends with <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , it must display its sincerity and let the Chinese people see actual actions and results .
For <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , the greatest interest concerning imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> lies in the <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> issue .
If imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> can stop its military sales to <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> , provide no support to <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> , and ensure peace across the <LOCATION>Taiwan Straits</LOCATION> , it will allow <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> to accomplish its great cause of national reunification .
If it refrains from meddling in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> 's internal human rights issues , and also does not intervene in other affairs such as <LOCATION>Tibet</LOCATION> , I believe that <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> will also sacrifice its other interests to reciprocate the good faith of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> !
Will imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> give up <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> ? Absolutely not !
Being used to being a hegemon , imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> likes to intervene in the internal affairs and human rights affairs of other countries , and <LOCATION>Taiwan</LOCATION> is the best chess piece for containing <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , so I believe imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> will not easily let go of it !
There is even less possibility that it will tolerate a Chinese challenge to its position as the world hegemon !
In the years to come , instead of becoming friends , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> will only become rivals and even enemies !
Therefore , it 's unnecessary to harbor any fantasies about imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> should fundamentally change its mentality , there is no need to fear imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> , and we should be ready for a military confrontations with imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> at any time .
Let 's win the respect of imperialist <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> and the whole world with our strength .
A peaceful rise is only our unilateral notion , because the big powers of the world will not accept the appearance of a powerful <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
Only baptized by war can <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> really become a world power .
The Chinese should be ever vigilant and not be deceived by the present peace , active war preparation is the only right choice ,
nly when our defense and military have become strong , will we be able to eradicate all aggressors , and only through the baptism of war can <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> become a truly powerful country .
In my personal opinion , there must be a war between <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> in the future !
What <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> needs to do is to cast away its illusions and get ready for war .
China Mobile is no doubt a monopolized operator in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , the biggest mobile phone market in the world . It has also expressed clearly its ambition to step outside the country and participate in global competitions .
Even though the performances of Chinese companies are not outstanding in the course of globalization , <PERSON>Wang Jianzhou</PERSON> , President and CEO of <LOCATION>China Mobile</LOCATION> , is determined to change all this .
On the eve of the Business Week CEO Forum held in <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> on <DATE>November 1</DATE> , <PERSON>Wang Jianzhou</PERSON> gave an exclusive interview to the editor of the Business Week .
He stated that the objective of <LOCATION>China Mobile</LOCATION> is to become a world - class company .
<PERSON>Wang Jianzhou</PERSON> , 57 , said in fluent English that <LOCATION>China Mobile</LOCATION> , which is listed on the <ORGANIZATION>Hong Kong Stock Exchange</ORGANIZATION> , has close to 300 million mobile phone users in mainland <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , an equivalent of the entire population of the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> .
This signifies that <ORGANIZATION>China Mobile</ORGANIZATION> occupies almost <PERCENT>70 percent</PERCENT> of the market share in mainland <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> .
<PERSON>Li Yanhong</PERSON> , <PERSON>Zhang Chaoyang</PERSON> , <PERSON>Shen Nanpeng</PERSON> , Ma Huateng ...
In the past 10 years , behind these Chinese high - tech magnates who emerged one after another was sure to be the shadow of the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> owned <ORGANIZATION>International Data Group</ORGANIZATION> ( IDG ) .
The annual IDG Conference was held in <LOCATION>Sanya</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>Hainan</LOCATION> on <DATE>November 3</DATE> .
Apart from the seven partners , who are called the ' Seven Swords ' inside IDG , the participants also included over 190 CEOs of companies that <ORGANIZATION>IDG</ORGANIZATION> invested in and representatives from investment banks and consulting agencies .
According to the practice of the past six years , after each <ORGANIZATION>IDG</ORGANIZATION> conference , there will always be some participants who make the list of magnates of the year .
I insisted on not paying him . Finally , he cracked and fled in panic .
However , I was also at the verge of collapse because the people 's police at 110 whom I looked forward to still had not arrived yet .
These days , overseas study has become popular . To friends and relatives , it 's a proud thing to be mentioned .
Children of the rich and government officials , who does n't want to enhance their status through overseas study ?
Let alone that getting oneself a western diploma will make getting a good job easier in the future . Even old dad and mom making a parade of it everywhere would look exceedingly good !
Nowadays , it is more often the case that those who do n't pass the university entrance exam and are wasting their days at home without doing anything are sent overseas . With a bit of " toughening up " , everything will be okay .
Wrong ! With a huge chunk of cash spent , the frightening thing is that the payoff falls far short of expectations .
I 've been in <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> for several years !
What I have experienced myself or , even more , what I have seen are the countless who have given up their studies year by year , those with wrecked health everywhere , those who sold their souls and even those who lost their lives .
Fuck you ! Go to hell ! Fuck your mother !
Complete and obvious bullshit ! More sinister than directly selling and buying infants !
Can <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> still be saved ?
The one - child policy is the most insidious policy , thoroughly antihuman and racially discriminatory , an open trampling on the right of survival right for Han people as a whole . Those who formulated and implemented this policy are all fascists ; they should be brought to trial at the <ORGANIZATION>International Court</ORGANIZATION> , and the people principally responsible for it should be hanged .
This guy really is a " representative " , a - ha .
As known to all , <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> have very low birth rates and mainly depend on migrants to maintain their population sizes and keep their populations young ; there is good economic development ;
In recent years , due to labor shortages , millions of black people and Southeast Asians have come to the southeast , and have caused varied degrees of deterioration in social order .
Just like <LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> , <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> depends on immigrants and at the same time pursues the one - child policy , making the planning policy look like a very clever policy !
<LOCATION>Shanghai</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Hong Kong</LOCATION> maintain their social development by absorbing migrants from other provinces , what will happen if <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> prepares herbal medicine by the prescribed method and absorbs foreigners ?
Do n't wait till the situation has become unmanageable and then drive away the gypsies as <PERSON>Sarkozy</PERSON> did ; German Chancellor <PERSON>Angela Merkel</PERSON> has just recently declared that <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> has failed to build a diversified society and will limit the development of the immigrant population ; now that the sheep have been stolen , no choice but to mend the fold !
Before long , the dividends for the population would wear out . As immigrant laborers swarmed in ( these people are not subject to family planning ) , the population would soon experience racial replacement , and <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> , as <LOCATION>Yugoslavia</LOCATION> did , would soon disintegrate !
The blacks , Arabs , and Vietnamese , one after another , would demand their rights , autonomy , and independence !
One after another , the local areas would become independent , as <LOCATION>Kosovo</LOCATION> did !
The minority peoples in <LOCATION>Xinjiang</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Tibet</LOCATION> can bear more children , causing the proportion of the Han people compared to the population of the frontier ethnic regions to decline quickly ;
The regiments of troops and Sichuan women that such national heroes as <PERSON>Zuo Zongtang</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wang Zhen</PERSON> took great pains to transplant into <LOCATION>Xinjiang</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Tibet</LOCATION> are being quickly exterminated by the one - child policy ; the undercurrents of <LOCATION>Xinjiang Independence</LOCATION> and Tibetan Independence are getting ever more rampant !
The family planning policy and the one - child policy have put the country in an dangerous as stacking eggs , and posed a threat to the survival of the nation .
Family planning has effectively reduced the Chinese population by 300 million , postponing the Day of 7 Billion by 3 years ; According to the plan of the <ORGANIZATION>Planning Commission</ORGANIZATION> , even if the Chinese population is reduced by <MONEY>1 billion</MONEY> , the Day of 7 Billion will be postponed for just another few years !
But the Chinese nation will be on the brink of extinction . Such selfless notions which nobody will have until evolving into a nonhuman creature , surprisingly , has become a reality in <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> !
The issues of population and ethnical structure are major issues for the survival of the country !
Family planning is part of the plan to massively exterminate the Han people , and the beginning of dividing <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> !
The family planning policy is extremely stupid and the ultimate in self - castration . It is unprecedented from a historic perspective and will be unmatchable in the future ; and in the global perspective , it is totally unique !
The self - harming policy fully embodies the malice of the enemy and the stupidity of the those in power , brings disasters to both the country and the people , is totally void of conscience , contributes nothing to the contemporary time , leaves a legacy of trouble for a long time in future , and will definitely become a joke that those throughout all history will ridicule !
The other day , <PERSON>Xinwen Lianbo</PERSON> reported that the difficulty for enterprises to hire workers has extended to the west and swept the whole country !
The family planning policy is extremely stupid , brings disasters to both the country and the people , and is totally void of conscience !
<ORGANIZATION>Improving Population Quality Requires Transferring Reproduction</ORGANIZATION> Rights to the Rich ?
Through free exchanges on the market , nearly everything can be bought and sold .
Today , the right to bear a second child is also becoming a popular product with the rich .
They have money to buy the right , to bear the child , and to raise the child .
As to these transfers and transactions of the right to bear a second child , let 's have a look at how the representatives argued and legally struggled with government officials at the " Two Meetings " .
Why did they propose such a transfer on the right to bear a second child ?
To this question , <PERSON>Li Xinghao</PERSON> - the author of this proposal , <ORGANIZATION>NPC</ORGANIZATION> representative and Chairman of <ORGANIZATION>Zhigao Group</ORGANIZATION> , said that such a transfer is beneficial to improving the quality of the population .
Transferred to which kind of person , exactly ?
Li Xinghao asserts that " In today 's society , people with strong educational backgrounds , the rich class , and civil servants have relatively high social status , relatively good economics means , and can ensure basic educational conditions and a good environment for the newborn population to develop in " .
Why is such transfer practical ?
Li <PERSON>Xinghao</PERSON> gave his own specific explanation from the angle of market supply and demand .
He said , " For a transfer , people are not classified into the rich and the poor , but into those who have a demand and those who do not .
He said that the original motive for this proposal was rooted in his discovery that some families legally allowed to bear a second child , due to their poverty and other reasons , would become even more impoverished if they were to do so ;
while some rich families had a strong desire to bear a second child but did not have the allowance to do so .
This transfer proposal by Representative Li is indeed very smart .
On the one hand , it helps the government to reduce and narrow the gap of wealth ;
n the other hand , it also solves the structural conflict of the reproduction right market - the poor have allowances but cannot afford the birth and upbringing , while the rich want to bear children but do n't have the allowance .
Based on Representative <PERSON>Li</PERSON> 's proposal , the rich will voluntarily reduce their per capita wealth by bearing and raising more children , while the poor will increase their per capita wealth by bearing and raising fewer children .
Through such transfers and transactions of the right to bear a second child between the rich and the poor , the government can unnoticeably narrow the ever - increasing gap between the poor and the rich without spending a single cent .
How can the wealth gap be narrowed through such transfer ?
This Representative Li has envisioned a fast track for the get - rich - first people to guide and assist the get - rich - later people . That is , " the allowance transferee shall give the transferor ' an entire sequence ' of help and support . "
" According to <ORGANIZATION>Li Xinghao</ORGANIZATION> 's plan , through lottery - type drawing , the transfer platform establishes a one - on - one guidance and assistance relationship between the transferee and the transferor .
As part of the assistance , the couple applying for the allowance to be transferred in to them will buy the transferring couple all the basic insurances currently required by the government , including social insurance , medical insurance , and personal accident insurance , and will continue to provide them with a minimum living guarantee for the rest of their lives .
Meanwhile , the applicant couple will also provide financial support for the education of the transferring couple 's child until he or she graduates from university .
What 's more , if the transferring couple intend to register as permanent urban residents , the applicant couple shall buy them a 35m2 socially subsidized apartment in the city where the applicants dwell , but all of the transferring couple 's land use rights in the countryside will belong to the applicant couple . "
What do our family planning officials think of this proposal that the State " utilize the transferring of rights to bear a second - child to improve the population quality and make the get - rich - first help the get - rich - later so as to realize common prosperity " ?
In response , " Yesterday , <PERSON>Zhang Feng</PERSON> , Director of <ORGANIZATION>Guangdong Provincial Family Planning Commission</ORGANIZATION> , made his stance clear to the media that the right to reproduce is absolutely not transferrable .
In the event that the right to reproduce is transferred , it would not only be a violation of law , but also bring moral questions if it involved a transaction . "
Through transferring their right to bear a second child and the concomitant obligations imposed on the transferees , the poor can get rich with the guidance and assistance from the get - rich - first class , if the proposal can pass and become law , the poor undoubtedly have found in the rich class , well - educated class , and the bureaucratic class an obedient son to provide for them up until they die . Marvelous indeed .
He claims it is not a transaction , but how can it be otherwise ? In this bundle of obligations for common prosperity , where is the dignity of the poor ?
Does not the bundle of obligations proposed by this Representative Li still imply a contract on the exchange and transaction of land use rights ?
Certainly , without such exchange of interests , why would the rich take an interest in providing for the children of the poor ?
If the legislature really wants to adopt this proposal on the premise of the get - rich - first class leading the get - rich - later class to become rich by giving them one - on - one guidance and assistance so as to improve our population quality and narrow our wealth gap , it must ensure fairness in such exchange of interests and during the transfer .
Transferred together with a wet nurse .
Following it with interest .
For a transfer of the right to marry , people are not classified into the rich and the poor , but into those who have a demand and those who do not . Since I discovered that some men who have a legal right to marry , due to their poverty and other reasons , would become even more impoverished if they did marry ;
Pillaging the flesh till the bones are seen ?
Interesting ... interesting
Logic of hooligans .
Directly transfer the wife
A pack of luxury cigarettes ranges from as little as a few tens of yuan to more than a hundred yuan , if you smoke a stick , you are puffing away one month 's salary for an ordinary worker .
If it was bought with public funds , it may be said that what they are smoking are not cigarettes but the " blood and sweat " of the taxpayers .
There are of course many reasons as to why we lag far behind in meeting our tobacco control objectives .
It is precisely because they are not using their own money that they usually smoke luxury cigarettes which are unaffordable for most people .
In our country , there are many civil servants who think their family name is " Gong " and such that every expense incurred by them , regardless of whether it is for public or private purpose , should be borne by the public . Therefore , consumption on public expenses can involve almost everything imaginable .
For instance , besides luxury cigarettes , other examples include luxury liquor , fine wining and dining , luxury cars , and overseas tours , and whatever luxury enjoyment and extravagant entertainment they can imagine , they would want to have them all and enjoy them to fullest , using public funds to settle the bill in full .
As for the remaining issues , we must ensure that the orders and prohibitions are fully enforced . If any civil servant dares to violate the law , he will be severely punished according to the law and regulations .
If this was really carried out in all localities at every level , there would be no cause to worry that the corrupt practice of consumption on public expenses , including smoking on public funds , cannot be curbed .
After deputies and committee members have moved into their quarters in the hotel , how would service staff greet them ?
Some greet them with " Deputy So - and - so " or " Committee Member So - and - so ; " while some call <ORGANIZATION>NPC</ORGANIZATION> deputies " chief , " which makes some deputies , especially deputies from the grass - roots level , feel somewhat embarrassed . Some deputies even request service staff to " not call me chief . "
Calling deputies and committee members who have moved into their quarters in the hotel " chief " is , of course , out of the hotel service staff member 's formal respect , but it has actually caused misunderstanding of the identity of deputy or committee member .
As major national events , the convening of the two conferences has clearly provided the path ahead for our development .
However , at the two conferences , according to common sense , the identity of " deputy " or " committee member " is generally used , that is , " Deputy xx " or " Committee Member xx . " But I cannot say much for the mention of " deputy as a chief . "
Through the subtlety of greeting , we can see common people 's sense of awe towards " deputies " and " committee members . "
Actually , when providing services to deputies and committee members , what 's wrong with being a bit simple ?
Would n't it appear more cordial to directly greet them as " Deputy xx " or " Committee Member xx ? "
After greeting them as chiefs , do n't you have a sense of awe and awkwardness ?
As deputies , they should equally treasure their own first identity . Deputy or committee member is neither an administrative official post nor a honorary title . This identity means enormous responsibility .
At the " times of the two conferences , " deputies and committee members should have an even heightened sense of responsibility . No matter what kind of social status you yourself have , remember firmly your own first identity and most important identity is a deputy , a committee member .
