French far-left killer leaves jail
ENSISHEIM, <LOCATION>France</LOCATION>, <DATE>April 14, 2010</DATE> (AFP) -
A former militant of the French far-left group Action Directe, <PERSON>Georges Cipriani</PERSON>, left prison on parole on <DATE>Wednesday</DATE> after 23 years behind bars for two high-profile murders.
A policeman at the scene confirmed to AFP the identity of <PERSON>Cipriani</PERSON>, 59, who left the prison in <LOCATION>Ensisheim</LOCATION> in northeastern <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> wearing a leather jacket and with long white hair.
Cipriani was one of four members of Action Directe sentenced to life in prison for the murder of <ORGANIZATION>Renault</ORGANIZATION> chief <PERSON>George Besse</PERSON> in <DATE>1986</DATE> and the head of government arms sales <PERSON>Rene Audran</PERSON> a year earlier.
The four included two women, <PERSON>Joelle Aubron</PERSON> who died of lung cancer in <DATE>2006</DATE> and <PERSON>Nathalie Menignon</PERSON>, who was paroled in <DATE>2008</DATE>.
A fourth member, <PERSON>Jean-Marc Rouillan</PERSON>, remains behind bars.
Cipriani left Ensisheim in a police vehicle bound for an open prison near <LOCATION>Strasbourg</LOCATION> where the police officer said he was due to do community service including working at a food bank as part of his parole.
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> president urges child safety after school killings
<LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION>, <DATE>June 1, 2010</DATE> (AFP) -
Chinese President <PERSON>Hu Jintao</PERSON> has called on the entire nation to do more to ensure the safety of children, state press said <DATE>Tuesday</DATE>, in comments that follow a spate of grisly school killings.
"The entire society must pay importance to the safety of children and do everything to safeguard our motherland's next generation," the People's Daily quoted Hu as saying.
Hu was speaking <DATE>Monday</DATE> as he toured a <LOCATION>Beijing</LOCATION> exhibit on transport and building safety with a group of schoolchildren on the eve of <ORGANIZATION>International Children</ORGANIZATION>'s Day, the report said.
His remarks come after a spate of bloody school attacks around <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> since late <DATE>March</DATE> which have left 17 people dead, including 15 students, and scores injured.
Experts say the senseless assaults reveal a <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> struggling to come to grips with rapid social change following decades of booming economic growth.
On <DATE>Sunday</DATE>, a 47-year-old unemployed man was executed for carrying out an assault on 32 people, mostly small children, at a kindergarten in eastern <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> in <DATE>April</DATE>.
The man, <PERSON>Xu Yuyuan</PERSON>, wielded a knife usually used to slaughter pigs.
Xu, who was sentenced to death on <DATE>May 15</DATE>, told the court his motive was to vent his rage against society after losing money gambling and in business dealings, and suffering setbacks in his personal life.
In <DATE>late April</DATE>, a former doctor who stabbed eight schoolchildren to death in a <DATE>March</DATE> school attack was executed.
Two other school assailants have committed suicide.
Premier <PERSON>Wen Jiabao</PERSON> said <DATE>last month</DATE> that long-standing social concerns including joblessness and a gaping rich-poor divide were partially to blame for the string of attacks.
"We need to resolve the deep-seated causes that have resulted in these problems," <PERSON>Wen</PERSON> said in an interview with <ORGANIZATION>Hong Kong-based Phoenix Television</ORGANIZATION>.
"This includes handling social contradictions, resolving disputes and strengthening mediation at the grassroots level."
Gadhafi attacks <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> in speech in <LOCATION>Italy
ROME</LOCATION> 2009-06-11 13:34:38 <ORGANIZATION>UTC</ORGANIZATION>
Libyan leader <PERSON>Moammar Gadhafi</PERSON> on <DATE>Thursday</DATE> urged the world to understand what motivates terrorists, and likened the <DATE>1986</DATE> U.S. strikes on <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> to <LOCATION>Osama</LOCATION> bin <ORGANIZATION>Laden</ORGANIZATION>'s terror attacks.
<PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON>, who was long accused of sponsoring terrorism, got tepid applause from the Italian lawmakers he addressed on the second day of a trip to <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION>'s former colonial ruler.
"It is not very intelligent to chase terrorists down the Afghan mountains or central <LOCATION>Asia</LOCATION>," <PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON> said in the hour-long speech.
"That's impossible.
We must look at their reasons."
He called for dialogue with terrorists, saying, "One must talk to the devil, if it brings about a solution."
Sarcastically, he asked, "What's the difference between the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> airstrikes on our homes and bin Laden's actions?"
If anything, he said, bin <ORGANIZATION>Laden</ORGANIZATION> is an outlaw, while the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> is a country that should abide by international law.
Former President <PERSON>Ronald Reagan</PERSON> ordered airstrikes on <LOCATION>Tripoli</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Benghazi</LOCATION> in <DATE>April 1986</DATE> after an attack on a disco in <LOCATION>Germany</LOCATION> killed three people, including two <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> servicemen.
The Libyans say the retaliatory attacks killed 41 people, including <PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON>'s adopted daughter, and injured 226 others.
The Libyan leader told the lawmakers he was being intentionally provocative "in order to try and understand acts of terrorism."
<PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON> had long been ostracized by the West for sponsoring terrorism, but in recent years sought to emerge from his pariah status by abandoning weapons of mass destruction and renouncing terrorism in <DATE>2003</DATE>.
<LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> has since agreed to pay compensation to the families of the <LOCATION>Berlin</LOCATION> disco victims as well as the families of the victims of the <DATE>1988</DATE> <ORGANIZATION>Pan Am</ORGANIZATION> 103 bombing over <LOCATION>Lockerbie</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION>, which killed 270 people, including 189 Americans.
Libyan <PERSON>Abdel Basset Ali al-Megrahi</PERSON> was convicted of blowing up the plane.
The <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> restored diplomatic ties with <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> in <DATE>2006</DATE> and removed the North African nation from the <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION> list of countries that sponsor terrorism.
<PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON>'s visit to <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> continued that process of emergence from international isolation.
But it also drew protests, including at La Sapienza university, where <PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON> was addressing a group of few hundred students.
The speech to lawmakers was likely to raise more controversy.
He had been set to speak inside the <ORGANIZATION>Italian Senate</ORGANIZATION>, a rare honor for visiting dignitaries.
But opposition lawmakers balked, forcing the speech to be moved to a palazzo next door.
<PERSON>Enrico Morando</PERSON>, a senator of the opposition Democratic Party, said <PERSON>Gadhafi</PERSON>'s presence at the <ORGANIZATION>Senate</ORGANIZATION> would have been a "humiliation of this country's democratic and republican spirit."
"Only those who have the credentials _ in terms of democracy and protection of human rights _ are entitled to speak to <ORGANIZATION>Parliament</ORGANIZATION>, the inviolable temple of democracy," he told La Repubblica newspaper.
Human rights organizations and other critics have also denounced a recent deal that allows <LOCATION>Italy</LOCATION> to send immigrants back to <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION> if they are intercepted at sea.
They also decried <LOCATION>Libya</LOCATION>'s treatment of the migrants and its poor human rights record.
Protests intensify in <LOCATION>Bolivia</LOCATION> over gasoline prices
LA PAZ, <LOCATION>Bolivia</LOCATION> 2010-12-31 01:59:04 <ORGANIZATION>UTC</ORGANIZATION>
Protests against a sharp increase in fuel prices intensified and turned violent in <LOCATION>Bolivia</LOCATION> on <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, as thousands of demonstrators demanded President <PERSON>Evo Morales</PERSON>' government repeal the hike.
Demonstrators filled the streets in La Paz and other cities to protest the higher prices, which were announced suddenly on <DATE>Sunday</DATE>, prompting an immediate <PERCENT>73 percent</PERCENT> jump in gasoline prices and an <PERCENT>83 percent</PERCENT> rise in prices for diesel.
It also led to rapid increases in transport and food prices in the Andean country.
Some demanded the resignation of <PERSON>Morales</PERSON>, a close ally of Venezuelan President <PERSON>Hugo Chavez</PERSON>.
It has been the most unpopular measure of <PERSON>Morales</PERSON>' five-year presidency.
Taxi drivers held a strike that largely paralyzed La Paz on <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, and protests were also held in the cities of <LOCATION>Cochabamba</LOCATION>, <PERSON>Santa Cruz</PERSON>, <PERSON>Potosi</PERSON> and <LOCATION>Oruro</LOCATION>.
The march in the capital began peacefully but clashes with police erupted when demonstrators tried to enter the main plaza where the government palace is located.
Police used tear gas to disperse the protesters, who hurled stones at officers, the vice president's office, a union headquarters and two ministry buildings.
In <LOCATION>El Alto</LOCATION>, neighboring the capital, demonstrators set afire a car and toll booths.
People lined a bridge while protesters raised fists demanding the measure be repealed.
Interior Minister <PERSON>Sacha Llorenti</PERSON> said disturbances in <LOCATION>La Paz</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>El Alto</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Cochabamba</LOCATION> left 15 police officers injured, two seriously.
A group of protesters burned a Venezuelan flag.
"We make a call for calm, for tranquility; there are police on patrol to guarantee security," <PERSON>Llorenti</PERSON> told a news conference.
Fuel prices had been frozen for six years, but the government said it could no longer afford to subsidize them, especially since much is smuggled across the border to neighboring countries.
Responding to the protests, <PERSON>Morales</PERSON>' government has announced steps aimed at mitigating the economic effects _ including <PERCENT>20 percent</PERCENT> salary increases for public workers aimed at offsetting higher fuel prices.
The government also announced new assistance to rice, corn and wheat farmers intended to increase production and bring down prices.
Demonstrators have called their protest the "gasolinazo."
Neighborhood protest leader <PERSON>Claudio Luna</PERSON> said in La Paz that the government's "message hasn't met the expectations of the population, and for that reason we're going to continue the protests."
He said demonstrators want prices lowered back to their former levels.
Bus drivers have also held sporadic protests this week, demanding the government further increase fares.
Authorities ordered raises of 60 to <PERCENT>80 percent</PERCENT> in public transport fares, but bus drivers argue that isn't enough to offset the higher costs.
Food prices have also risen <PERCENT>15 percent</PERCENT> in subsidized government markets, but that remained much less than in private supermarkets.
People seeking bargains lined up at a state-run food store in La Paz on <DATE>Thursday</DATE>.
Morales, meanwhile, said in a news conference that he is inviting advisers from <LOCATION>Paraguay</LOCATION>'s government to help formulate additional measures to lessen the blow of eliminating fuel subsidies.
exas has the most hard core criminal justice system in the country.
Is it a possibility there is another side to this?
Is it a possibility that this young man and his friend did not rape this girl?
Is it a possibility abc news has blown this out of proportion, twisted and distorted the facts?
Texas criminal courts and prosecutors do not coddle to anyone.
The football argument is an old one, not happening these days.
Players these days get 4 game suspensions for selling a t shirt on e-bay.
i'd never heard of this case until now.
So, i googled it to get more information.
Even the information that is available is fuzzy.
But it appears the prosecution struck a deal because of a lack of evidence.
It seems the prosecutor is saying that everyone involved was drunk/drinking and that the stories told had holes in them.......
all of them.
Hence, the 'slap on the wrists'.
I'm all for women/girls being able to do everything they want, in theory.
However, the reality of the situation is that 16 year old girls should not place themselves in situations like this (drinking to apparent excess) while at a party not chaperoned by an adult.
That said, young men should also not put themselves in that exact same situation because if you can't recount accurately what happened because you were drunk, you cannot say for sure what did or did not happen.
As for the race angle, it is unecessary.
This would have been no better or worse had the accused kids been white.
bingo
Why must we make this a race issue?
Really?
It's a horrible thing that happened.
Well then, why is it a HATE CRIME when a White person does it to a Black but not a HATE CRIME when it's the other way around?
I don't think it is a race issue either.
They need to throw these punks in jail!
Although you do make a good point that it's only a hate crime if a white person picks on a black person.
If it's the other way around it's no big deal for some reason.
If she was my daughter, those 2 punks that raped her would be found one day after football practice in a ditch with a bullet in their heads.
Amen!!!!
Because post racial <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> is showing itself...
he same people who don't not like <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> because of his race post this kind of crap.
You are an idiot.
I don't like obama because he is a socialist pig.
If the perps are black they are still guilty.
I am tired of thugs crying that they get in trouble just because they are black and that society made them do it, bull!!!!
They are thugs and deserve a bullet.
They should have been expelled from school at a minimum.
I guess you know the whole story and can make that objective assessment?
You need to learn the definition of socialist, then readjust your priorities.
Nevertheless, the whole stereotype you described is complete bullshit.
Nope.
Wasn't there.
My opinion is based on the information provided.
Welcome to a message board.
Funny you should say that.
A cousin of mine was raped a long time ago, the guy that did it commit suicide shortly after - blew his own head off with a shotgun.
BIG QUESTION!
Why the hell do guys rape women anyway?
Women are horny as hell!
All you have to do is be nice to them and they'll pretty much accomodate you in any way you want.
Yes, sometimes you have to give them time to think about it....
Besides which sex with women that are voluntarily engaged is an awful lot better.
Young guys need a talkin' to...
A talking to?
How about jail?
16 year old girls do not consent to gang rape.
No matter how "horny" or drunk they are.
Please tell me you're not speaking from experience.
You have to understand that in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION>, Football is King and good football players are gods who can do no wrong.
Worse than this has been swept under the rug for HS and college football stars there.
No, I don't have to understand.
Why is the title of your thread so insidious?
Why not a title lie "School Officials Screw over Rape Victim?"
That one would be more accurate.
Because this is not Your Thread to name.
Works for me.
And that question Wasn't Directed At You.
Still doesn't bend reality now does it?
Not only did 4 Blacks rape this girl, the main perp only received ANGER MANAGEMENT class with no jail time!
The girl was just 16, a cheerleader at <ORGANIZATION>Silsbee High School</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Texas</LOCATION>.
She was at a party in <DATE>2008</DATE> when football star <PERSON>Rakheem Bolton</PERSON>, fellow player <PERSON>Christian Roundtree</PERSON> and another boy pushed her into a bedroom and locked the door, held her down, and sexually assaulted her...
When others tried to enter the room, <PERSON>Bolton</PERSON> and <PERSON>Roundtree</PERSON> jumped out a window, leaving their clothes behind.
The girl filed charges, but that didn't put an end to her trauma.
Sphincteric school superintendent <PERSON>Richard Bain Jr.</PERSON> would make sure it only got worse.
When the girl returned to school, administrators decided the best course of action was for the girl to slink away in a corner and try not to be seen.
They told her to avoid the cafeteria and not take part in homecoming.
Out of sight, out of mind.
The kids were all teenagers, and the sex was claimed to be consensual.
I have no idea whether it was, and neither does anyone of this forum.
That remains to be seen.
So yes, the title of this thread does kind of bend reality.
Labour are a left wing socialist party.
They are pro immigration if it supports the economy and believe in equal rights for all individuals.
They are traditionally more likely and are known for allowing immigrants into the country - hence they were his target.
The labour party was responsible for the current state of immigration in the country, and in his own ideology, he wanted to take our future labour politicians (which those in the camp were potentially) from getting into power and allowing more in.
In his mind, by taking them out, he can prevent future immigration.
can't believe it, <LOCATION>norway</LOCATION> is such a friendly quiet country, this guy must be nuts they dont even have that many migrants, at least not compared to UK!
He basically hates Islam and believes that Islamic immigration is a huge threat to <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>.
He thinks that European politicians are allowing the colonisation of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION> by Muslims and so are all legitimate targets.
He thinks we need to deport all Muslims from <LOCATION>Europe Turkey North Iran</LOCATION> and Palestine.
He attacked his own kind because killing Muslims would lead to them being replaced by more Muslims.
So instead he decided to take out "the next generation of Left wing seeds".
In short he has wiped out a number of potential future left wing politicians.
He also sees himself a bit like a templar knight defending Christianity from Islam
This.
He isn't a White Supremacist though.
This is a bit of a myth. <LOCATION>Oslo</LOCATION> is a hugely multicultural and as far as I'm aware, <LOCATION>Norway</LOCATION> as a whole is about on par with the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION> in terms of different ethnic groups.
It's a myth British people seem to have that the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION> is one of the most multicultural places in <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>, when in reality <LOCATION>Sweden</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>the Netherlands</LOCATION> and possibly <LOCATION>Norway</LOCATION> are notably more so.
I'm not a fan of <PERSON>David Cameron</PERSON>.
Thanks to his government, I'll likely be paying 3x as much as I would for university.
I voted Labour yesterday, I am a Labour party member, with Scottish roots.
However, <PERSON>David Cameron</PERSON> *does* have a say, as do I, as do all of us, on whether we want the <ORGANIZATION>Union</ORGANIZATION> to remain.
<PERSON>David Cameron</PERSON> is the Prime Minister of the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION>.
He has every right, and indeed, it should be his job to defend and persuade the Scottish electorate and population that the <LOCATION>United Kingdom</LOCATION> should remain, that <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> should vote no to any such referendum.
I would vote no.
The world is changing, with a strengthening east and a weakening west.
If the UK were to split, we would all become weakened.
I agree, Scottish independence is a matter for the Scots, and should they vote for it, then that vote should be respected.
But, personally, I believe rather than a breakup, the union should be reformed, so there is equality for all the nations.
Bit of an off point - but I'll just say the 'West Lothian' question and leave you with that.
You argue that <PERSON>David Cameron</PERSON> should not be able to 'poke his big nose in' to the idea of Scottish independence - yet, Scottish MPs are able to do just that when certain English affairs are debated in Westminster (something English MPs are not able to do with Scottish affairs).
This is why there should be an appetite for reform within the <ORGANIZATION>Union</ORGANIZATION> - not a messy divorce that will leave us weakened, not strengthened.
I don't agree that Scottish should have a voice in Westminster concerning England-only matters.
Indeed, it would be far more pragmatic if we devolved the entire union -a parliament for every 5 or 10 million people in <LOCATION>England</LOCATION> perhaps?
(North/Midlands/London/South east/west?)
I'm sure there wouldn't be as much appetite for independence north of the border if the Scots felt that they weren't subordinate to a parliament situated hundreds of miles away that doesn't really represent them (<ORGANIZATION>Holyrood</ORGANIZATION> is overwhelmingly full of centre-left MSPs, yet we effectively have a centre right majority government in Westminster).
I'm not necessarily for or against independence.
I haven't really read into it enough to decide.
I fully support the decision to go independent though, if that is the outcome of the referendum, just as I would support the decision to remain in the union.
I'm not Polish.
That was my point.
My grandfather settled in the <LOCATION>Falkirk</LOCATION> area of <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> after the second world war (having served alongside British armed forces during the liberation of <LOCATION>Europe</LOCATION>).
I have Polish ancestry, the same way <PERSON>Cameron</PERSON> has Scottish ancestry.
The idea that <PERSON>Cameron</PERSON>'s ancestry should entitle him to vote on matters concerning the Scottish parliament is as ludicrous as my ancestry entitling me to vote in the <ORGANIZATION>Polish Sejm</ORGANIZATION>.
The argument that since <PERSON>Cameron</PERSON> is the prime minister of the UK, he should have a voice is more legitimate, but it is not an argument I agree with.
And if <PERSON>Brittany</PERSON> wished to split, that is an issue for those living in <LOCATION>Brittany</LOCATION>.
If <PERSON>Sarkozy</PERSON> isn't from <PERSON>Brittany</PERSON>, then his only job should be in ensuring that the split occurs legally.
The argument that the whole of the UK should vote on <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION>'s independence is like saying the whole of the <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> should get to vote if the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION> ever holds an in/out <ORGANIZATION>Eu</ORGANIZATION> membership referendum.
It's completely absurd and there's no justification for it.
And what's to say <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> will go bankrupt?
<LOCATION>Iceland</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Norway</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Denmark</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Finland</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Austria</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Lithuania</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Estonia</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Latvia</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Ireland</LOCATION> all have population sizes comparable to or smaller than <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION>, and all function well as independent states.
The Nordic countries have some of the strongest economies in the world, as does <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION>.
And the Irish economy was, until recently, booming.
<LOCATION>Iceland</LOCATION> is a very interesting example.
No major heavy industry, a population a little · over 1/3 of a million, universal healthcare and education (free at university level at state universities) and yet it manages to maintain one of the highest standards of living (arguably the highest) in the world.
Claiming that <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> would go bankrupt in no time is ridiculous.
It is entirely possible that <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> could follow the Nordic example if it ever decides to vote for independence.
People forget that <LOCATION>Edinburgh</LOCATION> is a reasonably large financial centre (relatively large for a country of 5 million) and that central <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> was a cradle for the industrial revolution.
Add to that revenue from hybrocarbon extractions in the north sea, fishing exports, and the ability to become reasonably self-sufficient in renewable energy (wind, tidal, hydroelectric -there's potential for it on <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION>'s rugged landscape) and I see no reason why <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> would be unable to function as an independent nation.
Apologies for misunderstanding your nationality.
I think the difference with <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION> to those Nordic economies is that <LOCATION>Scotland</LOCATION>'s current expenditure is higher than it would be ovule were to split.
It is enormously dependent on the support of the whole of the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION>.
It would have to scrap free university fees, it wouldn't have the <ORGANIZATION>NHS</ORGANIZATION>, thus UK infrastructure employs many Scots.
If it wasn't to go bankrupt it would certainly struggle for decades.
The <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> example just isn't the same at all.
The <ORGANIZATION>EU</ORGANIZATION> is not a country that actively supports each other economically (other than bailouts) as much as a country does, it isn't as socially connected, it employs an extremely small percentage of people, they aren't politically connected and have no national identity.
You're an idiot.
Loads of "far right" parties advocate high taxes, why?
Because it's based on jealousy.
Poor white folks blame their own poverty on the rich.
Hitler had an extensive welfare state, the <ORGANIZATION>BNP</ORGANIZATION> would punish the bankers to the point of destroying what is quite possibly the only real money maker the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION> has.
Lol banking is the only real money maker the <ORGANIZATION>UK</ORGANIZATION> has...
well firstly that isn't true and secondly they pay a pathetically small amount of taxes anyway so provide next to nothing to this country.
They pay a small percent by the overage sum is huge.
Where else does the money the government spend come from?
Do you really think that the West would lose to a bunch of countries that hate their own neighbours?
<LOCATION>India</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> hate each other and then there is <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> who hate both.
The <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> would just be destroyed if it was a total war.
If anything, the 'arrogance' would increase as a result.
There is no way in hell that <ORGANIZATION>NATO</ORGANIZATION> would lose to those countries.
<LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> is no match for <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> now.
And in the future <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> will be a mere annoyance than a real threat.
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>India</LOCATION> may have their differences, but they'll never go to war with each other.
They both stand to lose too much in the process.
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> is already wrapping a fist around the West's balls by buying up their debt and forcing the west to be economically dependent on them.
Very smart those Chinese.
<LOCATION>India</LOCATION> should eventually get in on the act, while weaning themselves off western investment, then when the time is right, they should use economic warfare to plunge western economies into chaos, crippling their financial power, and ultimately their military power.
After a few months so the West will be very vulnerable.
We've had to endure your cr*p for generations.
We're a patient people.
We don;t have to rely on military power alone, and we can wait until the time is right.
are you aware that the arabs and whites were rival powers until the white europeans overtook following the renaissance?
millions of white christians were enslaved by arabs.
pain, a white country was occupied by arabs for centuries.
arabs conquered the old eastern roman empire, they attempted to invade europe for centuries, finally being repelled at the battle of le panto.
white people <DATE>today</DATE> and victims of massive levels of anti white violence all across the western world.
america especially.
you are a racist.
Oh, I feel so sorry for the poor white people, they've had it sooooo bad.
Who the hell are the blacks, who were enslaved by whites to complain?
Who the hell are the Indians, who were enslaved and robbed blind by whites to complain?
They've been sooo bad to the whites over the years, haven't they?
And it's not like Blacks and Asians ever suffer discrimination at the hands of whites, is it?
Poor whites.
You have it so bad.
Idiot.
from all the other taxes businesses and people pay?
Barclays paid £113m in corporation tax in <DATE>2009</DATE> if you combine it with all the other banks it doesn't even make £1billion so you are saying that in <DATE>2009</DATE> the only money the government made was £1billion?
This is what happens when you dont believe in equality or understand how countries make money.
See people can learn to live with each other peacefully, not via segregation.
Who is this 'we'?
Okay, <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> has the debt bought up, but if they were to be destroyed who would chase it up?
<LOCATION>India</LOCATION> are no match for any Western country, not even <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION>.
Are you going to send the slum kids to attack, or how about the frail women?
The West has far more economic and military power than the <LOCATION>East</LOCATION>, to suggest otherwise shows that you're delusional.
1) Of course not, they haven't made them yet.
So on what basis will you attack <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION>?
That they MAY acquire nuclear weapons.
That is so ****ing silly.
If the UK were planning to abolish murder as a criminal charge in a few years time, could I go out and murder 100 people based on the intention, "Well, it's going to be abolished anyway".
2) I beg to differ.
It has repeatedly refused to declare several sites and when they were caught out they said they were going to declare them anyway.
Evidence?
3) As I said before here you are, making a pipsqueak about it and you only have to have an open mind to know that <LOCATION>America</LOCATION>'s being hypocritical.
I Know America AND <LOCATION>ISRAEL</LOCATION> are being hypocritical.
Yet no one is telling them that.
First of all to put it into context <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> didn't threaten <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION>.
It's been the warmongering on the mullahs' part after they decided they wanted <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> destroyed for some obscure reason because their ideology advocated it.
Iran is not an Arab country, the Israel-Arab conflict has absolutely nothing to do with <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION>.
The mullahs have no right funding proxies there because they are getting involved in something that has nothing to do with them.
The mullahs themselves see the Arabs as more of an enemy than <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> so this comparison is idiotic as there will never, ever be unity in the <LOCATION>Middle East</LOCATION> amongst Muslims and I hope there never is either.
(1) Yet for 30 years, they didn't do anything.
In fact, <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> has never even waged war against <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> which cannot be said for it's neighboring countries.
A very optimistic view.
<LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION> don't want the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> to throw its weight around so they're using their veto as a feeble show of strength.
By vetoing the criticism of <ORGANIZATION>Assad</ORGANIZATION>'s actions they want to show that they will not just follow <LOCATION>America</LOCATION>'s lead on this one.
(1) Feeble: <LOCATION>America</LOCATION>'s looking feeble.
They can't intervene and save their beloved "democracies in action" because of Russia/China.
There used to be a time when Americans would say "**** the world, we are doing this".
Defending itself against what?
Hezbollah was created by <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> and <PERSON>Khomeini</PERSON> decided to send <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Guards</ORGANIZATION> there to train militants as a 'resistance' group.
They don't seem to be doing much resisting by constantly firing rockets into <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> are they?
That's a whole different argument and frankly, this has nothing to do with it.
As I said before the mullahs have no right to poke their nose into the Arab-Israel conflict so whether <ORGANIZATION>Hezbollah</ORGANIZATION> attacked first or otherwise, it doesn't justify their actions.
The Afghan security force was created by the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> and the coalition.
Yet when they attack the people who they are "helping", they are labelled terrorists.
On the same scale, <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> has no RIGHT to poke it's nose at the Arab/Israel conflict if <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> hasn't got the same right.
Why are there different rules for one country and different rules for other countries?
Well it's obvious they'll say that but it's obvious they're after a bomb.
It's so they can throw their weight around without fear of reprisal from <LOCATION>America</LOCATION> or <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION>, not for use.
They shouldn't be allowed nukes, period.
As for an invasion, definitely not.
why is <LOCATION>israel</LOCATION> allowed nukes though.
Okay <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> should not have Nuclear weapons but <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> has no right to say it,
Its like a thief telling other people not to thieve because its illegal
The same way I saw the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> invading <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> instead of <LOCATION>Afghanistan</LOCATION> even though <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> have nukes.
Because <LOCATION>Pakistan</LOCATION> largely follows American orders.
The <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> assisted them in developing nukes in the first place.
As I said before <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> initiated it...
How?
For example?
The Shah seemed pretty content with staying out of it.
The <PERSON>Shah</PERSON>'s absolutism was a knock-on effect.
Mossadegh was going forward with social-democratic nationalism that had been popularised by <PERSON>Nasser</PERSON> and Arab leaders, and this led to the <DATE>1953</DATE> coup.
Where did I say that?
Note it was a question.
Why do you keep jumping to conclusions.
How did me explaining the reason for <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>'s veto somehow make me an American lover.
Bishy said that 'we'd see more positive results from <LOCATION>China</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Russia</LOCATION>' and I implied that the Chinese and Russians hold no sympathy for the Syrian people rather they want to maintain their control and not have the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> throw its weight around.
The way OP is written makes it a good guess you'd be backing US-Israel because you seemed to be agreeing with the proposed intervention by them, but fair enough if you're not.
Though based on what you're criticising <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> for, it should be quite a bit down on your priority list.
No.
I was just mentioning the <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> bit...
Why does the <LOCATION>US</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Israel</LOCATION> having favoured factions justify <LOCATION>Iran</LOCATION> to do the same.
It doesn't justify it, but it puts their actions into context.
On the same logic, being hit by someone doesn't justify hitting them, but it makes why you do (if you do) understandable.
UPDATING AN EMAIL LAW FROM THE PAST CENTURY
<PERSON>Steven Warshak</PERSON>, a <LOCATION>Cincinnati</LOCATION> businessman who built an empire selling male sexual enhancement drugs, was convicted of wire fraud several years ago, based in large part on his email correspondence, which authorities had extracted via a subpoena under a <DATE>1986</DATE> law governing electronic privacy.
A federal appeals court in <LOCATION>Ohio</LOCATION> later found, however, that the government had violated <PERSON>Warshak</PERSON>’s constitutional right to privacy.
The court said investigators should have convinced a judge that there was probable cause and obtained a search warrant, as though his messages had been stashed in a desk drawer.
Although the court let the conviction stand, the case highlighted the conflicting legal rules that govern electronic privacy.
<ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> is now set to clarify those rules, bringing that quarter-century-old law, the Electronic Communications Privacy Act, or <ORGANIZATION>ECPA</ORGANIZATION>, in line with the Internet age.
On <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, the <ORGANIZATION>Senate Judiciary Committee</ORGANIZATION> will start deliberating a measure that would require the government to get a search warrant, issued by a judge, to gain access to personal emails and all other electronic content held by a third-party service provider.
The current statute requires a warrant for emails that are less than 6 months old, but it lets the authorities gain access to older communications – or bizarrely, emails that have already been opened – with just a subpoena and no judicial review.
The law governs the privacy of practically everything entrusted to the Internet – family photos stored with a Web service, journal entries kept online, company documents uploaded to the cloud, and the flurry of emails exchanged every day.
The problem is that it was written when the cloud was just a cumulus in the sky.
Silicon Valley companies as well as advocacy groups from the political left and right have been lobbying for change for many years, and reform legislation seems to be gaining broad political support.
Even the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> appears to have approved one major change: requiring law enforcement to get a search warrant for all kinds of electronic content, no matter how long it has been in electronic storage or what exactly electronic storage means.
“Changing the law has become more of an imperative because of the growth of cloud computing, because everyone including members of <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> are storing sensitive info with third-party providers and they want it to be protected,” said <PERSON>Greg Nojeim</PERSON>, senior counsel at the Washington-based Center for Democracy and Technology, which is financed partly by <ORGANIZATION>Silicon Valley</ORGANIZATION> companies and which is part of a coalition pushing for reform.
“The technology is advancing and people realize the law has to keep pace.”
Updating the bill could have a broader impact on civil cases as well, clarifying who can gain access to emails, photos and Facebook posts in corporate litigation and divorce court.
It could also lay out clearer rules for government agencies like the <ORGANIZATION>Internal Revenue Service</ORGANIZATION> to follow to gain access to private citizens’ emails.
The agency told <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> recently that it seeks search warrants before reading taxpayer emails, though its written policy says otherwise, according to an information request filed by the <ORGANIZATION>American Civil Liberties Union</ORGANIZATION>.
Courts across the country, apparently baffled by how to apply the existing law, which applies to content held in “electronic storage,” have ruled in sometimes contradictory ways over the privacy of electronic material in both civil and criminal cases.
In one prominent case, <PERSON>Lee Jennings</PERSON> sued a relative of his wife who broke into his <ORGANIZATION>Yahoo</ORGANIZATION> account and ferreted out emails describing an extramarital affair that were later used as incriminating evidence in divorce proceedings.
<PERSON>Jennings</PERSON> claimed a violation of his privacy under the electronic privacy act, but the highest court in his home state of <LOCATION>South Carolina</LOCATION> held that his emails, which sat on <ORGANIZATION>Yahoo</ORGANIZATION>’s servers, were not held in “electronic storage” and therefore were not covered by the statute.
A federal court in <LOCATION>California</LOCATION> years earlier had ruled differently in another case, interpreting “electronic storage” far more broadly.
<PERSON>Jennings</PERSON>’ lawyer, <PERSON>Neal K. Katyal</PERSON>, a former acting solicitor general in the <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> administration, asked <ORGANIZATION>the Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION> to reconcile the dueling interpretations.
The court declined to hear the case this month, effectively leaving it to <ORGANIZATION>Congress</ORGANIZATION> to clarify the law.
Although the appeals court ruling in the <PERSON>Warshak</PERSON> criminal case is binding only in the <ORGANIZATION>6th Circuit</ORGANIZATION>, it has since become the default legal threshold for many Web companies.
Facebook says it turns over content created by users – pictures, posts, messages – only after it is served with a search warrant, though a subpoena suffices for basic subscriber information, including a user’s name and email address.
Twitter, too, says “requests for contents of communication require a <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> search warrant,” and it informs users when it receives a request for information from a government agency.
<ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION>, which operates email and cloud storage services, follows a similar practice, insisting on a search warrant for “content,” including documents, photos, email and instant messages.
With a subpoena, the company can divulge a user’s Internet Protocol record, though, which can be used to establish a person’s location.
“The law is so old it doesn’t account for how we have turned into a digital society,” said <PERSON>Bryan Schilling</PERSON>, a lawyer at <ORGANIZATION>Microsoft</ORGANIZATION>.
He offered an offline analogy: “If somebody had a storage unit, law enforcement would be required to get a search warrant,” he said.
“It’s the same thing now, as we store more and more of our content in the cloud, consumer or enterprise.”
The original sponsor of the <DATE>1986</DATE> law, Sen. <PERSON>Patrick Leahy</PERSON>, <LOCATION>D-Vt.</LOCATION>, has called its overhaul his top priority for the year.
He and Sen. <PERSON>Mike Lee</PERSON>, <LOCATION>R-Utah</LOCATION>, have introduced a measure requiring law enforcement to obtain a warrant for all electronic content, including emails, regardless of how old they are.
That overhaul is backed by an unlikely coalition.
Amazon and <ORGANIZATION>Google</ORGANIZATION>, which offer cloud-based services to consumers and businesses, are lobbying for the change, along with startups like Evernote and Tumblr, which operate modern-day private diaries.
They have joined with advocacy groups as diverse as the <ORGANIZATION>American Civil Liberties Union</ORGANIZATION> and Americans for Tax Reform.
The issue of email privacy received the greatest attention last year, when Gen. <PERSON>David H. Petraeus</PERSON>, the former director of the <ORGANIZATION>Central Intelligence Agency</ORGANIZATION>, resigned after an inquiry into his email correspondence turned up evidence of an extramarital affair.
He and his biographer, <PERSON>Paula Broadwell</PERSON>, had exchanged amorous correspondence in a “draft” folder of a shared Gmail account, apparently to elude detection.
Those draft messages, because they had not been transmitted across the Internet, could have been viewed by federal authorities with nothing more than a subpoena, according to current law.
GEORGE JONES IN REAL LIFE AND REAL TIME
Early in <DATE>1977</DATE>, a couple of years after he and <PERSON>Tammy Wynette</PERSON> had divorced, the country music star <PERSON>George Jones</PERSON> played a show at the <ORGANIZATION>Stardust Inn</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Waldorf</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Md.</LOCATION>, his first in the <LOCATION>Washington</LOCATION> area in several years.
I was then a young pop music critic at <ORGANIZATION>The Washington Post</ORGANIZATION>, so it fell to me to write a profile of the notoriously hard-drinking singer.
What followed was an experience so intense, so remarkable for its raw emotional force, that I could not help but think of it <DATE>Friday</DATE>, when it was announced that <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> had died in a <LOCATION>Nashville</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Tenn.</LOCATION>, hospital at the age of 81.
That <DATE>weekend</DATE> I learned two important things about Jones: that there was very little distance between him and his songs, and that the same qualities that made him a great artist also made his life a torment.
In those days he was still unashamedly carrying a torch for <PERSON>Wynette</PERSON>, who had left him because, as she put it in legal papers she filed, he “drinks to such an extent that he becomes completely and absolutely unmanageable.”
On stage that <DATE>weekend</DATE>, he reworked songs like “She Thinks I Still Care” and “Picture Me Without You” so that they included references to her, making them almost embarrassingly personal, as if she were in the audience and he was singing only to her.
But it was on his tour bus between sets that I saw <PERSON>George Jones</PERSON> more achingly and nakedly vulnerable than any performer I have ever encountered, before or since that night.
He was dressed in a flashy leisure suit and wore a pair of glittering diamond rings on his left hand, including one with his initials, but as he talked about <PERSON>Wynette</PERSON> and how much he still loved her, he began to weep.
I don’t think he was drunk.
He talked about how he was trying to stay dry for <PERSON>Tammy</PERSON>, who by that time had already re-married and divorced again.
Within a year or two, he would develop a cocaine habit that would send his career off the rails, but there was no sign of that either.
This was just <PERSON>George Jones</PERSON> in real life and real time.
It is hard today, in a time when irony has become a dominant cultural mode and artists are screened from reporters by phalanxes of handlers, to imagine so public a breakdown happening or a celebrity letting his pain be so visible.
But <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> wasn’t ashamed or embarrassed by that display, and when he went back to the stage for a second set of what he described to me as “sad, sloppy tear-jerkers,” his singing was even more passionate and inspired, with his twangy, somewhat nasal voice cracking in all the right places with what had to be genuine feeling, not artifice.
Over a career that lasted nearly 60 years, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> recorded more than 100 albums, and over and over again, he didn’t just sing the songs that were given to him.
In the best of his recordings, as on that night, he also inhabited them, so that anyone listening to him could be sure: He really means it, he has really lived this song about heartbreak or hangovers and knows what it means, poor soul.
As someone who grew up in <LOCATION>Chicago</LOCATION> listening mostly to the blues, I had no special fondness for country music, whose only local outlet in those days was the radio station WJJD.
But seeing <PERSON>George Jones</PERSON> live for the first time that cold night in southern <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION> was a revelation, because in his own highly idiosyncratic way he showed himself to be no less soulful a singer than <ORGANIZATION>Howlin</ORGANIZATION>’ <PERSON>Wolf</PERSON> on something like “How Many More Years” or <PERSON>Otis Redding</PERSON> on “I’ve Been Loving You Too Long.”
Despite all the drinking and drug binges that would dog his career, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> never lost that gift.
In <DATE>2009</DATE>, assigned to write a profile of the Canadian singer-songwriter <PERSON>Leonard Cohen</PERSON> for this newspaper, I walked into <PERSON>Cohen</PERSON>’s <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> hotel suite to find him playing one of Jones’ late-career gems, “Choices,” on his iPod.
Cohen expressed great admiration for <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> and then recited one of the song’s most powerful verses:
I was tempted
By an early age I found
I liked drinkin’
Oh, and I never turned it down
There were loved ones
But I turned them all away
Now I’m living and dying
With the choices I made
@In part because of his consistent “nipping,” as he called it, Jones never enjoyed the crossover success of his contemporaries <PERSON>Johnny Cash</PERSON> and <PERSON>Merle Haggard</PERSON>, and so his passing will probably not have the broad cultural resonance that Cash’s did.
But he was, hands down, a superior singer, a fact obvious to everyone in the country music field: As <PERSON>Waylon Jennings</PERSON> once sang, “If we all could sound like we wanted to, we’d all sound like <PERSON>George Jones</PERSON>.”
But even within the confines of “pure country,” whatever that term might mean today, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> did not stand still.
He began his career very much in the mold of his idol <PERSON>Hank Williams</PERSON>, singing tunes about honky-tonks and carousing.
He never lost his affection for that genre, but over the years he also evolved into a master of ballad singing, especially on his duets with <PERSON>Melba Montgomery</PERSON> and <PERSON>Wynette</PERSON>, both before and after they were married.
And though a brief late ‘50s flirtation with rockabilly didn’t pan out, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> also knew how to rock.
It’s almost forgotten now, but he and <ORGANIZATION>Elvis Presley</ORGANIZATION> once were co-headliners on a <LOCATION>Louisiana Hayride</LOCATION> tour, and generations of rock 'n’ roll bands, including ones I played in, have covered songs like “Why Baby Why,” “White Lightning” and “The Race Is On” and found them to be guaranteed crowd-pleasers.
Beginning in the <DATE>1980s</DATE>, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON>, with the help of his fourth wife, <PERSON>Nancy Sepulvedo</PERSON>, pulled himself out of his tailspin.
But by then the country music mainstream had begun to move on to more polished styles, and <PERSON>Jones</PERSON>’ visceral approach fell out of fashion.
In recent years, <PERSON>Jones</PERSON> had thought of himself as a relic, and expressed bitterness at what he saw as the disregard for what he represented.
All that may be true, but it can’t – and doesn’t – dim the magnificence of his achievements, any more than his personal weaknesses and demons did.
DEATH ROW INMATE ’ S REQUEST FOR DNA TESTING IS REJECTED
The state of <LOCATION>Mississippi</LOCATION> rejected on <DATE>Monday</DATE> a request to submit physical evidence for DNA testing made by a prisoner scheduled to be put to death <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> <TIME>evening</TIME>.
<PERSON>Willie J. Manning</PERSON>, convicted in <DATE>1994</DATE> of murdering two college students, had been repeatedly rebuffed in the courts as he sought to have DNA tests performed on certain crime scene evidence.
But the most recent requests came about because of two letters sent by the <ORGANIZATION>Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> in recent days to the prosecutor who handled <PERSON>Manning</PERSON>’s trial.
The letters concerned the trial testimony of an <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> expert asked to examine “hair fragments” found at the scene of the murders.
The expert testified that in this case he could determine only that the hairs came from an African-American but that hair comparison analysis was capable, given better samples, of matching a hair to a particular individual.
Manning is black; the murder victims were white.
The prosecutor cited this testimony several times in his closing arguments.
In a letter dated <DATE>May 2</DATE>, <ORGANIZATION>the Justice Department</ORGANIZATION> said the expert’s testimony about the general capability of hair analysis – that it could match a hair to a specific individual – was erroneous and “exceeded the limits of the science.”
Then, in a letter dated <DATE>May 4</DATE>, the department further said that such analysis could not “determine” that a hair came from a person of a certain race, as the expert testified at one point, only that the hair “possesses certain traits that are associated with a particular racial group.”
The <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> offered in both letters to perform DNA testing on the hair fragments.
Manning’s lawyers argued that these letters constituted new evidence and thus that the hairs, as well as other evidence collected at the scene including a rape kit and fingernail scrapings, should be submitted for DNA testing before <PERSON>Manning</PERSON> is put to death.
In the response denying the requests, the state attorney general, <PERSON>Jim Hood</PERSON>, called the new requests a “red herring,” saying that the letters did not “represent new evidence,” nor did they repudiate the testimony given by the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> expert in <DATE>1994</DATE>.
Manning’s lawyers are still lobbying the governor for a stay of execution.
On <DATE>Friday</DATE>, <PERSON>Manning</PERSON>’s brother and the <ORGANIZATION>Mississippi Innocence Project</ORGANIZATION> filed suit to preserve all the physical evidence for DNA testing even if the execution is carried out.
FOCUS TURNS TO THREE SUSPECTS IN BELGIAN DIAMOND ROBBERY
<LOCATION>PARIS</LOCATION> – Investigators in three countries continued unraveling the plot behind a brazen <MONEY>$50 million</MONEY> diamond robbery in <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION>, focusing <DATE>Thursday</DATE> on a Swiss lawyer, a real estate businessman and a French luxury car exporter with a prison record for fraud.
After a series of raids <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> and <DATE>Wednesday</DATE> in <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>France</LOCATION>, the authorities started releasing some of the more than 30 men who were arrested and questioned in connection with the <DATE>Feb. 18</DATE> robbery, in which armed men in police suits attacked a Zurich-bound plane minutes before takeoff from the <LOCATION>Brussels</LOCATION> airport.
Investigators in <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION> suspect that a critical organizer in the plot was <PERSON>Marc Bertoldi</PERSON>, 43, a French car exporter whose listed address was in a wealthy seaside neighborhood of <LOCATION>Antibes</LOCATION> on the Cote d’Azur and who owns a restaurant in <LOCATION>Casablanca</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Morocco</LOCATION>.
He was arrested <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> in <LOCATION>France</LOCATION> and remains in prison, awaiting a hearing <DATE>May 16</DATE> in <PERSON>Metz</PERSON> for extradition to <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION>.
Investigators said <PERSON>Bertoldi</PERSON>’s arrival in <LOCATION>Geneva</LOCATION> after the theft had provided a critical breakthrough in the inquiry.
After <PERSON>Bertoldi</PERSON>’s arrest, the police trailed an unidentified Swiss lawyer and a real estate owner <DATE>Wednesday</DATE> as they made an exchange of a key to a cellar where some of the stolen diamonds were discovered.
Bertoldi’s lawyer, <PERSON>Olivier Rondu</PERSON>, said <DATE>Thursday</DATE> that his client denied the accusations against him and was willing to be extradited to <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> to confront the charges.
“He has a surprising position that he wants to go to <LOCATION>Belgium</LOCATION> as quickly as possible to explain himself, because he says he has done nothing,” <PERSON>Rondu</PERSON> said.
“He denies participating in the robbery at <LOCATION>Brussels</LOCATION> airport.”
Rondu also confirmed that his client had been convicted in the past for fraud and robbery and had served a prison term.
In <LOCATION>Switzerland</LOCATION>, where eight people were arrested <DATE>Wednesday</DATE>, the real estate owner and the Swiss lawyer remained in detention.
<PERSON>Francois Canonica</PERSON>, a lawyer for the Swiss lawyer, also denied any wrongdoing on his client’s part, telling a Swiss newspaper, <ORGANIZATION>Tribune de Geneve</ORGANIZATION>, “My client has faith that ultimately he will be acquitted.”
BRITAIN AND <LOCATION>ECUADOR</LOCATION> MAY DISCUSS ASSANGE CASE
<LOCATION>LONDON</LOCATION> - The Ecuadorean foreign minister is due to travel to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> this month and has offered to meet his British counterpart to discuss the impasse over the <PERSON>Julian Assange</PERSON> case, officials from both countries said on <DATE>Monday</DATE>.
Assange, the founder of the anti-secrecy group WikiLeaks, has been holed up for nearly a year in the tiny <ORGANIZATION>Ecuadorean Embassy</ORGANIZATION> here, stymying British attempts to extradite him to <LOCATION>Sweden</LOCATION>.
The Swedish authorities want to question Assange in connection with accusations that he sexually assaulted two women, but he has said he fears that the Swedes will in turn send him to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> to answer questions about his role in helping disseminate classified government information via <ORGANIZATION>WikiLeaks</ORGANIZATION>.
The development concerning Assange came on the same day as the court-martial of Pfc. <PERSON>Bradley Manning</PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION>Army</ORGANIZATION> private accused of passing on sensitive diplomatic and military information, was scheduled to begin in <LOCATION>Maryland</LOCATION>.
Manning has pleaded guilty to 20 of the 22 charges against him, but he has not admitted to the most serious charge, aiding the enemy.
Manning has said he gave the material to <ORGANIZATION>WikiLeaks</ORGANIZATION>, which then helped disseminate it.
Assange has never acknowledged that <PERSON>Manning</PERSON> was his source.
A spokesman for the Ecuadorean government said last week that the foreign minister, <PERSON>Ricardo Patino</PERSON>, planned to travel to <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> on <DATE>June 16</DATE>, three days before <ORGANIZATION>Assange</ORGANIZATION>’s first anniversary in the embassy, and to meet with <ORGANIZATION>Assange</ORGANIZATION>.
“<ORGANIZATION>The Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Ecuador</ORGANIZATION> has informed <LOCATION>U.K.</LOCATION> authorities that Mr. <PERSON>Patino</PERSON> will be in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and has offered to meet with Foreign Secretary <PERSON>William Hague</PERSON> to discuss the case of <PERSON>Julian Assange</PERSON>,” the spokesman said.
A spokesman for the <ORGANIZATION>British Foreign Office</ORGANIZATION> said it was informed of <PERSON>Patino</PERSON>’s trip on <DATE>Friday</DATE> and was “considering” his request for a meeting with <LOCATION>Hague</LOCATION>.
“<LOCATION>U.K.</LOCATION> government officials have been in regular contact with representatives of the Ecuadorean government, both in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Quito</LOCATION>, about Mr. <PERSON>Assange</PERSON>,” the <ORGANIZATION>Foreign Office</ORGANIZATION> said in a statement.
“We hope the visit will contribute to our joint commitment to finding a diplomatic solution to this issue.”
Last week, <ORGANIZATION>Reuters</ORGANIZATION> quoted <PERSON>Patino</PERSON> as saying his government was preparing a document in which it would argue that <LOCATION>Britain</LOCATION> is legally obliged to give Assange permission to travel to <LOCATION>South America</LOCATION>.
SOUTH AFRICAN LEADER CITES 'PROGRESS' IN MANDELA'S CONDITION
<LOCATION>JOHANNESBURG</LOCATION> - After four days in the hospital battling a lung infection, former President <PERSON>Nelson Mandela</PERSON> of <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION> “is responding better to treatment,” President <PERSON>Jacob Zuma</PERSON> told <ORGANIZATION>Parliament</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Cape Town</LOCATION> on <DATE>Wednesday</DATE>.
“We are very happy with the progress that he’s now making, following a difficult few days,” <PERSON>Zuma</PERSON> said.
It was the first report of an improvement in <LOCATION>Mandela</LOCATION>’s condition since he was admitted to a hospital in <LOCATION>Pretoria</LOCATION> early <DATE>Saturday</DATE> after suffering a recurrence of a persistent lung ailment, a legacy of the tuberculosis he contracted during the 27 years he was imprisoned for opposing apartheid.
His health has been frail lately, and this hospitalization was his fourth in the last seven months.
Government officials in the last few days had been more downbeat, describing <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s condition as “serious but stable” with no improvement.
Mandela, 94, is being treated in an intensive care unit, where close family members have been visiting him regularly.
Among them are his daughters, his former wife <PERSON>Winnie Madikizela-Mandela</PERSON> and his grandson <PERSON>Mandla Mandela</PERSON>.
His current wife, <PERSON>Graça Machel</PERSON>, canceled a speech in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> to be by his side.
<PERSON>Mandla Mandela</PERSON>, who is a traditional leader in the <LOCATION>Eastern Cape</LOCATION> village where his grandfather was born, spoke to reporters outside <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s home.
“My grandfather is the father of the nation,” he said.
“He’s embraced by the global community, and we appreciate the support that we’ve received.”
As an underground leader of the banned <ORGANIZATION>African National Congress</ORGANIZATION>, <PERSON>Mandela</PERSON> was convicted of treason 49 years ago <DATE>Wednesday</DATE>.
He was sentenced to life in prison, but was released in <DATE>1990</DATE> as the government, under intense international pressure, began negotiating with <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>ANC</ORGANIZATION>.
He retired from public life in <DATE>2004</DATE>, and has not been seen in public since <DATE>2010</DATE>, when <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION> hosted the World Cup.
MILITANTS ATTACK <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION>
COMPOUND IN <LOCATION>SOMALIA
MOGADISHU</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Somalia</LOCATION> - Militants staged a deadly assault on a <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION> compound here <DATE>Wednesday</DATE>, the latest in a series of attacks that have chipped away at the security gains the Somali capital has experienced in recent years.
The assault began when <ORGANIZATION>Shabab</ORGANIZATION> militants blew up a pickup truck rigged with explosives outside the compound, witnesses said.
Somali and <ORGANIZATION>African Union</ORGANIZATION> troops responded to the scene.
The ensuing firefight lasted more than an hour, punctuated by a series of blasts.
<LOCATION>Somalia</LOCATION>’s minister of interior and national security, <PERSON>Abdikarim Hussein Guled</PERSON>, told reporters that the dead included four foreigners, four Somalis working for the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION> as security personnel, as well as the attackers.
In a statement, <LOCATION>Somalia</LOCATION>’s prime minister, <PERSON>Abdi Farah Shirdon Saaid</PERSON>, condemned “the senseless and despicable attack on innocent <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION> civilians.”
Mogadishu has experienced a period of relative calm since <ORGANIZATION>African Union</ORGANIZATION> forces and the Somali army pushed back the <ORGANIZATION>Shabab</ORGANIZATION>, leading it to announce a hasty retreat from the city in <DATE>2011</DATE>.
The militant group vowed to shift tactics more toward guerrilla assaults, assassinations and suicide bombings.
Militants “are now in complete control of the entire compound and the battle is still ongoing,” the <ORGANIZATION>Shabab</ORGANIZATION> said on its Twitter feed during the attack.
“Inside the compound are several clueless foreigners who were lulled into a false sense of security by a strong disinformation campaign!”
The <ORGANIZATION>Shabab</ORGANIZATION>, who have sworn allegiance to al-Qaida, said that the group’s Martyrdom Brigade had carried out the attack.
The <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION> compound sits on a busy stretch of road near the airport.
An ambulance worker, <PERSON>Abdirisak Moumin</PERSON>, said that he had collected 13 wounded civilians, six of whom died from their injuries.
<PERSON>Nicholas Kay</PERSON>, the <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION> special representative for <LOCATION>Somalia</LOCATION>, was outside the compound at a meeting nearby when the attack occurred.
He called the attack an act of terrorism intended to derail <LOCATION>Somalia</LOCATION>’s drive toward recovery after decades of war and instability.
While the <ORGANIZATION>United Nations</ORGANIZATION> would review its security procedures, “the <ORGANIZATION>U.N.</ORGANIZATION> is committed to its mission,” <PERSON>Kay</PERSON> said in a telephone interview.
“We’re here to help and we’re here to stay.”
VIGIL FOR MANDELA CONTINUES AS FAMILY MEMBERS HOLD EMERGENCY MEETING
<LOCATION>JOHANNESBURG</LOCATION> - Singing crowds gathered outside the hospital where <PERSON>Nelson Mandela</PERSON>, <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION>’s former president, lay in a critical state for a third consecutive day <DATE>Tuesday</DATE>, as family members held an emergency meeting at his ancestral village.
Mandela’s eldest daughter, <PERSON>Makaziwe</PERSON>, at least two grandchildren and clan elders gathered at <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s retirement house in <LOCATION>Qunu</LOCATION>, the remote southern village where he grew up, according to news media reports.
The subject of the meeting was not publicly disclosed, but <PERSON>Naplisi Mandela</PERSON>, an elder of the <PERSON>Mandela</PERSON> family, told the <ORGANIZATION>South African Press Association</ORGANIZATION> that they had gathered to discuss “delicate matters” - a euphemism widely interpreted to mean preparations for <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s death.
Meanwhile, in <LOCATION>Pretoria</LOCATION>, doctors continued to treat Mandela for a lung ailment that he contracted on <LOCATION>Robben Island</LOCATION>, the notorious apartheid-era prison where he spent much of his 27 years behind bars until his release in <DATE>1990</DATE>.
He was hospitalized <DATE>June 8</DATE>, his fourth hospitalization since late last year.
In a statement, President <PERSON>Jacob Zuma</PERSON> said <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s condition was unchanged.
On <DATE>Sunday</DATE>, he visited <PERSON>Mandela</PERSON> and pronounced that his state had deteriorated from stable to critical.
Noting that <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s 95th birthday is on <DATE>July 18</DATE>, <LOCATION>Zuma</LOCATION> urged <LOCATION>South Africans</LOCATION> to celebrate his achievements.
Still, after 18 days of anxious vigil, many appeared to be steeling themselves for the worst.
Larger-than-usual crowds gathered at the gates of the <ORGANIZATION>Mediclinic Heart Hospital</ORGANIZATION> to pay tribute to <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>, as people dropped off cards at a growing shrine and sang songs.
“There is no one like you, <PERSON>Nelson Mandela</PERSON>,” one group sang in the Sotho language.
The emotional scenes were part of a perceptible shift in the national mood.
Until recently, many <LOCATION>South Africans</LOCATION> had avoided talking about <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>’s fate, calling it culturally inappropriate to speculate about any ailing figure, much less one as revered as <ORGANIZATION>Mandela</ORGANIZATION>, who played a central role in <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION>’s transition from white-led minority rule to historic multirace elections in <DATE>1994</DATE>.
But now many are openly talking about the prospect of bidding him farewell.
Mandela’s declining condition came as President <PERSON>Barack Obama</PERSON> prepared to arrive in <LOCATION>South Africa</LOCATION> on <DATE>Friday</DATE> on the second leg of an African tour that will also take him to <LOCATION>Tanzania</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Senegal</LOCATION>.
But the South African government said a planned meeting between <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> and <PERSON>Mandela</PERSON> - both the first black leaders of their countries - now looked unlikely.
<PERSON>MICHAEL MASTROMARINO</PERSON>, DENTIST GUILTY IN ORGAN SCHEME, DIES AT 49
<PERSON>Michael Mastromarino</PERSON>, a former dental surgeon who became a tabloid sensation when he was charged with running a <MONEY>$4.6 million</MONEY> enterprise that plundered tissue and bone from corpses at funeral homes and sold them for transplants and research, died on <DATE>Sunday</DATE> at <ORGANIZATION>St. Luke’s Cornwall Hospital</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Newburgh</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>N.Y</LOCATION>. He was 49 and still serving a prison term.
The cause was complications of metastatic liver cancer, <PERSON>Mario Gallucci</PERSON>, <PERSON>Mastromarino</PERSON>’s lawyer, said.
The technology that allows the transplantation of critical organs also enables the far more common transplantation of tissue: bone can be used to repair fractures, veins for heart bypass surgery, and tendons and ligaments can restore mobility.
Harvesting organs is allowed in <LOCATION>New York state</LOCATION>, provided the donor does not carry a potentially communicable disease, the survivors approve and the person is not too old.
But there are nowhere near enough willing donors to meet the demand for tissue, so the profit from one body can reach six figures.
Mastromarino became licensed by <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> state to supply tissue banks and manufacturers of biological surgical instruments after his dental license was suspended in <DATE>2002</DATE> because of a drug addiction.
He established a network of undertakers, whom he paid up to <MONEY>$1,000</MONEY> per corpse, and soon took on assistants and formed a business based in <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION>, <ORGANIZATION>Biomedical Tissue Services</ORGANIZATION>.
He reportedly made <MONEY>$10,000</MONEY> to <MONEY>$15,000</MONEY> per body.
But <PERSON>Mastromarino</PERSON> harvested organs and tissue from bodies without consent from the survivors, the authorities said, and removed material from people with cancer, HIV and other diseases.
He then forged paperwork, including consent forms and death certificates, to make the cause of death and age acceptable.
The police began investigating irregularities at the <ORGANIZATION>Daniel George & Son Funeral Home</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Bensonhurst</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION>, in <DATE>2005</DATE>.
News reports included lurid details, like what the police called a secret room in the funeral home equipped with specialized surgical equipment; leg bones replaced by PVC pipe so bodies would appear intact at viewings (this procedure is common in lawful bone removal); and the fact that one of the victims was <PERSON>Alistair Cooke</PERSON>, the British journalist and former host of “Masterpiece Theater,” whose arm and leg bones were taken even though he had had cancer.
Mastromarino was charged in <DATE>2006</DATE>, along with two of his workers and an embalmer.
He pleaded guilty in <DATE>2008</DATE> to numerous charges of enterprise corruption, reckless endangerment and body stealing and was sentenced to 15 to 30 years in prison.
He and his wife, <PERSON>Barbara</PERSON>, agreed to pay <MONEY>$4.6 million</MONEY> to the district attorney’s office, to be distributed among the victims’ relatives.
<PERSON>Michael Mastromarino</PERSON> was born in <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION> on <DATE>Sept. 16, 1963</DATE>.
He graduated from <ORGANIZATION>the University of Pittsburgh</ORGANIZATION> and the <ORGANIZATION>New York University College of Dentistry</ORGANIZATION>.
Mastromarino had surgical offices in <LOCATION>New Jersey</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION>.
He was a co-author, with <PERSON>Michael R. Wiland</PERSON>, of the book “Smile: How Dental Implants Can Transform Your Life.”
<PERSON>Mastromarino</PERSON>, who was divorced, is survived by two sons, <PERSON>Michael</PERSON> and <PERSON>Jerry</PERSON>.
As for <PERSON>Cooke</PERSON>, his daughter, <PERSON>Susan Cooke Kittredge</PERSON>, said in an article in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION> magazine that “he would have been just horrified” by the illegal harvesting.
But, she said, “at the same time, he would have appreciated the Dickensian nature of it.”
EXTRADITED COLOMBIAN TO FACE CHARGES OF DRUG TRAFFICKING
A Colombian who has been described by his country’s president as “the last of the great kingpins” was extradited to the <LOCATION>United States</LOCATION> from <LOCATION>Colombia</LOCATION> on <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> to face charges that he manufactured large quantities of cocaine that he then trafficked to the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> and elsewhere.
<PERSON>Daniel Barrera</PERSON> is to be arraigned <DATE>Wednesday</DATE> and <DATE>Thursday</DATE> in <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> district courts in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> and <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION>, where he faces separate indictments.
After those prosecutions, he will be arraigned in <LOCATION>Miami</LOCATION> on additional charges, the authorities said.
Barrera, also known as <LOCATION>El Loco</LOCATION>, was arrested in <DATE>September</DATE> in <LOCATION>Venezuela</LOCATION> as a result of a complex operation that included Colombian and Venezuelan authorities, the <ORGANIZATION>CIA</ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION>Drug Enforcement Administration</ORGANIZATION> and the British intelligence.
He was later sent to <LOCATION>Colombia</LOCATION>, and his extradition was announced by the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> attorneys in the three jurisdictions and other officials, including <PERSON>Raymond W. Kelly</PERSON>, the police commissioner of <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>; and <PERSON>Michele M. Leonhart</PERSON>, the head of the <ORGANIZATION>DEA</ORGANIZATION>.
An indictment in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> says that Barrera relied on two Colombian terrorist organizations to carry out his operations, buying raw cocaine paste from members of the <ORGANIZATION>Revolutionary Armed Forces of Colombia</ORGANIZATION>, or <ORGANIZATION>FARC</ORGANIZATION>, and processing it in laboratories in areas controlled by another group, to which he paid fees.
Barrera’s organization produced upward of 400 tons of cocaine a year, “enriching itself and the two terrorist organizations it paid off,” said <PERSON>Preet Bharara</PERSON>, the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION>.
<PERSON>Loretta E. Lynch</PERSON>, the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> attorney in <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION>, said <PERSON>Barrera</PERSON>’s organization was “marked by its worldwide reach, ruthless criminality and staggering profits.”
Barrera is charged in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> with one count of narcotics importation conspiracy, which carries a maximum sentence of life in prison.
He faces a money laundering conspiracy charge in <LOCATION>Brooklyn</LOCATION>.
His lawyer declined to comment.
Officials have said that <PERSON>Barrera</PERSON>, while residing in <LOCATION>Venezuela</LOCATION>, changed his appearance through plastic surgery, slept in different places and burned his fingertips to try to make it impossible to identify him.
EGYPT CALLS FOR NEW LOOK AT MORSI PRISON ESCAPE
<LOCATION>CAIRO</LOCATION> - <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION>’s new rulers gave new credence to a court case against the ousted president, <PERSON>Mohammed Morsi</PERSON>, and members of the Muslim Brotherhood on <DATE>Thursday</DATE> over their escape from prison during the uprising that toppled his predecessor, <PERSON>Hosni Mubarak</PERSON>.
The case was transferred from an appeals court to the <ORGANIZATION>State Security</ORGANIZATION> prosecutor for further investigation.
No charges have been filed as yet.
Its acceptance by powerful prosecutors follows the arrest of many Muslim Brotherhood members and is a new blow to the group by the military-backed government.
The detentions have been criticized by rights groups and the <PERSON>Obama</PERSON> administration, which spent <DATE>Thursday</DATE> walking back remarks made early in the day by a <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION> spokeswoman, <PERSON>Jen Psaki</PERSON>, seeming to criticize <PERSON>Morsi</PERSON> as undemocratic and in so doing seeming to validate the military’s move to oust him.
At her regular <ORGANIZATION>State Department</ORGANIZATION> briefing <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, asked about the reactions, <PERSON>Psaki</PERSON> said she had been “referring to all of the voices that have been - we have heard coming - the millions, I should say, coming from <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION>, and how strongly they have voiced their views about his rule.
But beyond that is up for the Egyptian people to determine.”
The renewed investigation of <PERSON>Morsi</PERSON> and members of the Muslim Brotherhood dates to the uprising that led to the ouster of Mubarak in <DATE>2011</DATE>.
Morsi and other Brotherhood leaders were arrested <DATE>Jan. 28</DATE> and held in the <ORGANIZATION>Wadi Natroun</ORGANIZATION> prison north of <LOCATION>Cairo</LOCATION>, until they escaped <DATE>two days later</DATE>.
The case languished after <PERSON>Morsi</PERSON> was elected last year in the country’s first free presidential race, although local news outlets and <PERSON>Morsi</PERSON>’s opponents accused militants from <ORGANIZATION>Hamas</ORGANIZATION>, the <ORGANIZATION>Brotherhood</ORGANIZATION>’s Palestinian offshoot, of freeing their colleagues.
Morsi has not been seen publicly since his ouster <DATE>July 3</DATE>.
It is unclear where he is being held, or whether he and the others will face the charges in court.
The ouster of <PERSON>Morsi</PERSON> and the subsequent suppression of the Brotherhood has enraged the group’s members and led to a spate of scapegoating attacks by Muslim extremists against Christians they accuse of supporting his fall, rights activists said.
While tensions between the Christian minority and extremist elements in the Muslim majority are not new, attacks have been reported across the country - in the northern <LOCATION>Sinai Peninsula</LOCATION>, in a resort town on the <LOCATION>Mediterranean Coast</LOCATION>, in Port Said along the <ORGANIZATION>Suez Canal</ORGANIZATION> and in isolated villages in upper <LOCATION>Egypt</LOCATION>.
No special session, but protesters leave <ORGANIZATION>Capitol
Times/Herald Tallahassee Bureau</ORGANIZATION>
<LOCATION>TALLAHASSEE</LOCATION> — They weren’t able to persuade Gov. <PERSON>Rick Scott</PERSON> to call a special session on the controversial ''stand your ground’' law.
But the student activists known as the Dream Defenders drew national attention to their cause by holding the longest sit-in demonstration at the <LOCATION>Florida Capitol</LOCATION> in recent memory.
On <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, the Miami-based group announced that their record-setting protest is over — for now, at least.
''After 31 days and 30 nights, we are leaving the Capitol for our next phase,'' Dream Defenders executive director <PERSON>Phillip Agnew</PERSON> said.
<PERSON>Agnew</PERSON> said the group would register thousands of new voters in the coming months and return to the Capitol for legislative committee hearings in the <DATE>fall</DATE>.
The Dream Defenders’ occupation of the Capitol began <DATE>July 16</DATE>, three days after <PERSON>George Zimmerman</PERSON> was acquitted in the shooting death of <ORGANIZATION>Trayvon Martin</ORGANIZATION>, an unarmed teenager from Miami-Dade.
They promised to stay until <PERSON>Scott</PERSON> convened a special session on ''stand your ground’' and several other criminal justice issues.
''We said if (<PERSON>Scott</PERSON>) would not give us a seat at the table, we would sleep on the floor until (he) gave us what we deserved,'' <PERSON>Agnew</PERSON> said.
Scott met with the protesters <DATE>July 18</DATE> but refused their demands.
The Dream Defenders tried to persuade state lawmakers to call the session themselves, but they couldn’t muster the 96 votes needed.
As of <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, 42 lawmakers had voted in favor of holding the session, 90 voted against, and 28 had yet to vote.
This week, <ORGANIZATION>House Speaker Will Weatherford</ORGANIZATION> called for the group’s departure.
The Dream Defenders claimed several victories, including a promise from <LOCATION>Weatherford</LOCATION> to hold a hearing on the ''stand your ground’' law this <DATE>fall</DATE>.
The group also secured meetings with the <ORGANIZATION>Florida Department of Law Enforcement</ORGANIZATION> to discuss racial profiling, <PERSON>Agnew</PERSON> said, and began a dialogue with the state <ORGANIZATION>Department of Juvenile Justice</ORGANIZATION> on the disproportionate number of young African-American men in prison.
<PERSON>Agnew</PERSON> said the <ORGANIZATION>Dream Defenders</ORGANIZATION> had not been pressured to wrap up their protest by the governor’s office or state law enforcement officials.
The Capitol Police who had watched over the group, <PERSON>Agnew</PERSON> added, ''deserved a raise.''
The state spent a total of <MONEY>$153,630</MONEY> on police overtime throughout the protest, according to <ORGANIZATION>FDLE</ORGANIZATION>.
The <ORGANIZATION>Dream Defenders</ORGANIZATION> didn’t anticipate their stay would last a month or that singer <PERSON>Harry Belafonte</PERSON>, rapper <PERSON>Talib Kweli</PERSON> or civil rights leaders <PERSON>Jesse Jackson</PERSON> and Julian Bond would join them in the Capitol.
''Gov. <PERSON>Scott</PERSON>, through his inaction, created a new group of leaders who will have a lasting effect on <LOCATION>Florida</LOCATION>,'' said state Rep. <PERSON>Alan Williams</PERSON>, a <LOCATION>Tallahassee</LOCATION> Democrat who mentored the group.
When they packed up their belongings and left the Capitol <DATE>Thursday</DATE> <TIME>evening</TIME>, the young activists wondered aloud if there had been some level of divine intervention along the way.
On <DATE>Wednesday</DATE>, the state <ORGANIZATION>Department of Management Services</ORGANIZATION> announced plans to test the fire alarm system in the <LOCATION>Capitol</LOCATION>.
The testing would last from <TIME>8 p.m. until midnight</TIME>, and involve an ''incredibly loud, high-pitch noise,'' according to a press release.
But before the testing began, the building adjacent to the Capitol was struck by lightning.
The <ORGANIZATION>Department of Management Services</ORGANIZATION> decided to perform maintenance on that building’s fire alarm system instead.
''I don’t know how to explain it,'' Dream Defender <PERSON>Steven Pargett</PERSON> said.
''Some things are just meant to happen.''
Times/Herald staff writers <PERSON>Tia Mitchell</PERSON> and <PERSON>Michael Van Sickler</PERSON> contributed to this report.
A PINK-SLIP THANKS FOR A MAJOR DECISION
On Baseball);
When <PERSON>John Gaherin</PERSON>, the chief labor negotiator for <ORGANIZATION>Major League Baseball</ORGANIZATION>, arrived for a meeting with the chief of the players union and baseball’s arbitrator, he carried an envelope in the pocket of his suit jacket.
It was two days before <DATE>Christmas 1975</DATE>, not a time to be conducting serious business, but <PERSON>Gaherin</PERSON> and <PERSON>Marvin Miller</PERSON>, the executive director of the union, knew why <PERSON>Peter Seitz</PERSON>, the arbitrator, had summoned them.
They knew that the subject of the meeting would be as serious a bit of business as baseball had ever experienced, and <PERSON>Gaherin</PERSON> went to the meeting prepared.
<PERSON>Seitz</PERSON> had informally telegraphed his decision in a grievance case, and now he would formally hand his written opinion to the two men.
As soon as he did, <PERSON>Gaherin</PERSON> handed <PERSON>Seitz</PERSON> the envelope.
“You’re fired,” it said in effect.
Such is the perilous life of impartial arbitrators in baseball and other professional sports.
Either side - the league or the union - has the right to fire them.
Like managers, they are hired to be fired.
“He told me he had expected as much,” <PERSON>Michael Seitz</PERSON>, <PERSON>Peter</PERSON>’s son, said in a recent telephone interview.
“His feeling was there was no other way to decide the case, because the baseball owners had been stupid in assuming that when they didn’t have a player under contract, they still had a contractual hold on him.”
<PERSON>Fredric R. Horowitz</PERSON>, a 64-year-old lawyer from <LOCATION>Santa Monica</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Calif.</LOCATION>, is the latest to take a turn.
He will arbitrate <PERSON>Alex Rodriguez</PERSON>’s appeal of his 211-game suspension.
While arbitrators pay for their decisions, which anger either the owners or the players, they don’t always receive credit for the significance of their decisions.
<PERSON>Seitz</PERSON>, for example, was responsible for creating free agency in baseball with his decision in the <DATE>1975</DATE> Andy Messersmith-Dave McNally grievance, but I believe, as <PERSON>Marvin Miller</PERSON> used to complain, that some reports in the news media, including in The <ORGANIZATION>New York Times</ORGANIZATION>, mistakenly credited other cases: <PERSON>Curt Flood</PERSON>’s <DATE>1970</DATE> lawsuit against baseball and <PERSON>Catfish Hunter</PERSON>’s <DATE>1974</DATE> grievance against <PERSON>Charlie Finley</PERSON>.
Flood’s suit challenged the game’s reserve clause, the rule that bound a player to his team until he was traded, sold or released.
Hunter’s grievance contended that <PERSON>Finley</PERSON>, the <LOCATION>Oakland</LOCATION> Athletics’ owner, had breached his contract.
The <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON> case was exactly what the union argued, a breach-of-contract case.
Finley had not paid the premium on <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON>’s annuity, as stipulated in his contract, <PERSON>Richard Moss</PERSON>, the union lawyer, said, and the pitcher should be a free agent as a result.
<PERSON>Seitz</PERSON>, in his first year as baseball’s arbitrator, agreed with <PERSON>Moss</PERSON>’ argument and declared <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON> a free agent.
A year later, when <PERSON>Seitz</PERSON> ruled in the Messersmith-McNally grievance, he did not cite the <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON> decision as a basis for this decision.
As a breach-of-contract case, it affected no player but <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON>.
No other player could gain free agency based on <PERSON>Seitz</PERSON>’s decision on <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON>.
“It didn’t change the mind of a single owner,” <PERSON>Miller</PERSON> said of the <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON> decision in one of the many conversations we had on the subject.
"The owners’ position on free agency was the same after the <PERSON>Hunter</PERSON> case as it was before.''
Nor, <PERSON>Miller</PERSON> added, did the Flood case affect the owners’ thinking on the reserve clause and free agency.
The reserve clause had forever been the tie that bound players to their teams, whether they liked it or not.
Flood did not like it, and when the <ORGANIZATION>St. Louis Cardinals</ORGANIZATION> traded him to <LOCATION>Philadelphia</LOCATION>, he opted to sue the commissioner rather than go to the <LOCATION>Phillies</LOCATION>, contending that he should have the right to play where he wanted.
The suit went all the way to the <ORGANIZATION>U.S. Supreme Court</ORGANIZATION>, where Flood lost.
The owners always argued that elimination of the reserve clause would ruin baseball, <PERSON>Miller</PERSON> said, and <ORGANIZATION>Flood</ORGANIZATION>’s loss in the lawsuit emboldened them to maintain their position.
As heroic as Flood was in pursuing his lawsuit, it fell well short of having an effect.
Its failure was one of the reasons the owners were so confident of winning the Messersmith-McNally grievance in court when they appealed <PERSON>Seitz</PERSON>’s decision, which said players could be free agents if they played the renewal year in their contract without signing a new contract.
What the owners failed to understand, in their inexperience in labor matters, was that judges rarely overruled an arbitrator’s decision, doing so only if an arbitrator’s authority had been exceeded.
The clubs and the commissioner have not done particularly well before arbitrators in instances where players have been suspended for conduct off the field.
That history continued last year when <ORGANIZATION>Shyam Das</ORGANIZATION> overturned <PERSON>Ryan Braun</PERSON>’s 50-game suspension.
Das was fired after his <PERSON>Braun</PERSON> ruling.
Baseball would have preferred settling all of the doping cases stemming from the investigation into Biogenesis, an anti-aging clinic that is believed to have distributed banned substances to baseball players.
The union also seemed eager to settle.
But <PERSON>Rodriguez</PERSON> has appealed his 211-game suspension.
Given the volatility of the <PERSON>Rodriguez</PERSON> case, it would not be surprising if <PERSON>Horowitz</PERSON>’s first major case were his last.
FORMER JPMORGAN EMPLOYEE SURRENDERS IN '<LOCATION>LONDON</LOCATION> WHALE' CASE
Weeks after the <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> government charged <PERSON>Javier Martin-Artajo</PERSON>, a former JPMorgan Chase employee, with hiding trading losses that ultimately reached more than <MONEY>$6 billion</MONEY>, he had his first day in court <DATE>Tuesday</DATE> as he surrendered to Spanish authorities and kicked off what could be a lengthy extradition process.
Martin-Artajo, a Spaniard who worked in the bank’s <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> office, was released soon after his surrender and arrest.
He agreed to remain at the disposal of the Spanish judiciary, but it was unclear whether his passport was confiscated to prevent him from leaving the country, according to a person briefed on the matter.
The criminal charges stem from a risky bet at JPMorgan’s chief investment office in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION>, where Martin-Artajo worked.
The bet involved so-called credit derivatives, which allow traders to bet on the perceived health of companies like <ORGANIZATION>American Airlines</ORGANIZATION>.
When the bet soured in the <DATE>spring of 2012</DATE>, prosecutors claim, Martin-Artajo and <PERSON>Julien Grout</PERSON>, a lower-ranking employee, deliberately overstated the value of their positions to hide <MONEY>hundreds of millions of dollars</MONEY> in losses.
The two were charged with wire fraud, falsifying bank records and contributing to false regulatory filings.
Prosecutors also charged them with conspiracy to commit those crimes.
The arrest in <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION>, the latest development in an episode that left a rare stain on JPMorgan’s once-stellar reputation, underscores the challenge <LOCATION>U.S.</LOCATION> authorities face in their pursuit of the traders.
After announcing charges this month against Martin-Artajo and Grout, federal prosecutors and the <ORGANIZATION>FBI</ORGANIZATION> in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> have encountered logistical hurdles.
British police issued an arrest warrant for Martin-Artajo at the behest of authorities in <LOCATION>New York</LOCATION>, and then visited his house in <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> only to find that he was gone.
According to his lawyers, <ORGANIZATION>Martin-Artajo</ORGANIZATION> left <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> “on a long-planned vacation” to his native <LOCATION>Spain</LOCATION> without knowing of the pending charges.
Grout, for his part, left <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> this year for his native <LOCATION>France</LOCATION>, which typically does not extradite its citizens.
His lawyer, <PERSON>Edward Little</PERSON>, explained that his client also spent a brief period in <LOCATION>the U.S.</LOCATION>, where his wife’s family lives.
According to a person close to the case, both of the former traders have indicated through their lawyers that they are open to extradition but only if prosecutors recommend bail.
Prosecutors have not charged a third trader, nicknamed “the <LOCATION>London</LOCATION> Whale.”
That trader, <PERSON>Bruno Iksil</PERSON>, has reached a deal with the authorities in <LOCATION>Manhattan</LOCATION> that will spare him charges as long as he cooperates against his two former colleagues.
LEADER OF FAR-RIGHT PARTY IN <LOCATION>GREECE</LOCATION> IS JAILED
<LOCATION>ATHENS</LOCATION>, <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION> - The leader of the extreme-right Golden Dawn party was returned to custody <DATE>Thursday</DATE> after appearing before a Greek magistrate on charges of setting up a criminal organization, part of the government’s crackdown on a party described by Greek and European authorities as neo-Nazi and violent.
The magistrate’s order to remand <PERSON>Nikos Michaloliakos</PERSON>, the first political party leader to face jail since <LOCATION>Greece</LOCATION>’s seven-year military dictatorship ended in <DATE>1974</DATE>, came a day after three of his fellow lawmakers facing similar charges were released from custody and told not to leave the country, and a fourth was ordered held pending trial.
During more than six hours of testimony in an <LOCATION>Athens</LOCATION> courtroom, <PERSON>Michaloliakos</PERSON> condemned the murder last month of a 34-year-old hip-hop artist and anti-fascist, <PERSON>Pavlos Fyssas</PERSON>, by a self-professed supporter of Golden Dawn, and said he did not know whether members of the party were involved in violence, according to a court official.
“I condemn the murder, like I condemn violence in general,” he was quoted as saying.
“I am not a Nazi.”
Leaving court early <DATE>Thursday</DATE>, <PERSON>Michaloliakos</PERSON> was defiant.
“Long live Golden Dawn!
Victory!” he declared as his wife, <PERSON>Eleni Zaroulia</PERSON>, another Golden Dawn member of <ORGANIZATION>Parliament</ORGANIZATION>, cried, “You’re a diamond!” and his daughter, <PERSON>Ourania Michaloliakou</PERSON>, urged him, “Don’t buckle, don’t give in!”
Michaloliakos was transferred to the capital’s high-security Korydallos prison later in the day along with <PERSON>Yiannis Lagos</PERSON>, another Golden Dawn lawmaker.
